Again
また
Big
大きい
Go
行く
Time
時間
For sophisticate
洗練された人向け
what goin
何が起こっているの
Bonjour
おはよう
It is
それは
not
いいえ
Our feast of knowledge has held many circles
私たちの知識の饗宴は多くのサークルを開催してきました
This effect is also very good
この効果もなかなか良いですね
loved by everyone
みんなに愛されてる
what about today
今日はどうですか
Well, that today we have a special invitation to this
さて、今日は特別なご招待です
Director of the Institute of Taiwan History
台湾歴史研究所所長
come give us a talk on this
これについて話しに来てください
The title of this speech is called
この講演のタイトルはこう呼ばれています
Japanese Memory in Later Well-known Taiwanese Folk Beliefs
後の有名な台湾の民間信仰における日本人の記憶
I just saw this listener
このリスナーを見ました
There is this well-known after we are famous in Taiwan
台湾で有名になったらこんなのもありますよ
Professor Dexing Shang
シャン・デキシン教授
Professor Dexing
徳興教授
I want to ask why he came. Looking at the topic, it turns out that he will definitely come to listen to this speech.
なぜ彼が来たのか聞きたいのですが、話題を見ると、彼は間違いなくこのスピーチを聞きに来ることがわかりました。
Before this speech begins, I, Zhao Li, would like to introduce the brief introduction of today's speaker
この講演が始まる前に、私、趙立が本日の講演者の簡単な紹介をしたいと思います。
Professor Xie Guoxing, actually an old friend of mine
謝国興教授、実は私の古い友人です
He is just like what Chen I said just now, he is the researcher and director of the Institute of Taiwan History of our academy
彼は先ほど言った陳さんと同じで、当学院の台湾史研究所の研究者兼所長です。
He's also actually a peace fellow at the Institute of Modern History.
彼は実は近代史研究所の平和研究員でもある。
His research areas are modern Chinese history, Taiwan's social and economic history, and Taiwan's folk beliefs.
研究分野は中国近現代史、台湾の社会経済史、台湾の民間信仰。
He received a Ph.D. from the National 40,000 University at a very early age, and established the Institute of Modern Research as an assistant researcher, associate researcher, researcher, etc.
若くして国立4万大学で博士号を取得し、助研究員、准研究員、研究員などとして現代研究所を設立。
His academic works are very rich
彼の学術著作は非常に豊富です
The 80th Anniversary of the Academia Sinica in Pursuit of Excellence
卓越性を追求する中央研究院80周年
There are also eight special books such as Fucheng Shengshi, News Cake and his pages.
Fucheng Shengshi、News Cake、彼のページなど、8 冊の特別な本もあります。
And editor-in-chief of Taiwan's digital point long results for sustainable management
持続可能な経営のための台湾のデジタルポイントロング結果の編集長
Many books on history have also published a lot of academic papers
歴史に関する書籍も多く、学術論文も多数出版されています
In fact, he is an expert in corporate history in Taiwan.
実は彼は台湾の企業史の専門家でもある。
He once studied the rise of the well-known Tainan state
彼はかつて有名な台南州の隆盛を研究したことがある
He also studied the biography of Mr. Chen Hongyan
彼はまた、陳紅燕氏の伝記も研究しました。
Mr. Chen Hongyan knows the older generation
陳紅燕氏は古い世代を知っている
He is the founder of the Taipei Air Camp
彼は台北航空キャンプの創設者です。
He was also a well-known literati during the Japanese occupation
彼は日本占領時代には著名な文人でもあった
Well, apart from his outstanding academic achievements, the senior
さて、彼の優れた学業成績とは別に、先輩は
Administrative qualifications are also quite rich
行政資格も充実
Chen Dannen, special assistant to the dean of the hospital and legislators
陳丹念（チェン・ダンネン）病院長特別補佐および国会議員
general affairs officer of the head office
本社総務担当者
Deputy Director of the Institute of Modern History and all cultural centers of the Institute
近代史研究所および同研究所のすべての文化センターの副所長
convener, etc.
コンビナーなど
Then this shows his academic qualifications and his administrative experience
次に、これは彼の学歴と管理経験を示します
is a very rich person
とても裕福な人です
Then I think this is not clean
それから、これはきれいではないと思います
The most important thing is to appreciate this report he gave us today
最も重要なことは、今日彼が私たちにくれたこの報告に感謝することです
Thank you, director
ありがとう、監督
Vice President Peng
彭副総統
Colleagues in this hospital and friends outside the hospital
当院の同僚と院外の友人
Thank you very much for coming today
本日はご来場いただき誠にありがとうございました
We also thought that there are so many people
私たちもこんなに人がいるのかと思いました
At first it was
最初はそうでした
Vice President Huang
黃副院長
ask if i can come
来られるか聞いてください
He should have said he assigned me to give a lecture
彼は私に講義をするよう割り当てたと言うべきだった
then i readily agree
それなら私もすぐに同意します
I think this popular science thing
これは人気のある科学のことだと思います
us
私たち
if there happens to be something readily available
たまたますぐに手に入るものがあれば
Can come
来ることができます
come to report to you
あなたに報告に来てください
that should be a meaningful thing
それは意味のあることのはずだ
That just happened to remind me of some of the things I've done recently
たまたま最近やったことを思い出したんです
Issues related to Taiwanese folk beliefs
台湾の民間信仰に関する問題
There is one that not everyone knows
誰もが知らないものがあります
but may be of interest
でも興味があるかもしれない
so i wholeheartedly agree
だから私は心から同意します
That didn't occur to me that I remembered talking to me months ago
数か月前に私と話していたことを思い出したとは思いませんでした
Because I was too busy, I suddenly thought of it
忙しすぎてふと思いついた
So I am still changing my ppd this afternoon
今日の午後もPPDを変更しています
Hope to bring you today
今日はあなたをお届けしたいと思っています
Learn more about Taiwanese society
台湾社会についてもっと知る
this postcolonial
このポストコロニアル
It's an academic term
学術用語です
I'm not going to discuss today
今日は議論するつもりはない
Theories about postcolonialism
ポストコロニアリズムに関する理論
This is not a very interesting topic
これはあまり興味深い話題ではありません
Academia would be more interested
学術界はもっと興味を持つだろう
Ordinary people don't necessarily need to know
一般人は必ずしも知る必要はない
Why do you combine post-colonial Japan with folk beliefs?
なぜ植民地後の日本と民間信仰を組み合わせるのですか？
It is because everyone knows that the general impression of Taiwanese society is that they have a good impression of Japan.
それは台湾社会の一般的な印象が日本に対して良い印象を持っていることを誰もが知っているからです。
If compared to South Korea that was once colonized
かつて植民地だった韓国に比べたら
Or compared to China, which once had a war with Japan
あるいはかつて日本と戦争をした中国と比較して
Taiwan looks different
台湾の様子が違う
Many people will think that the reason why Taiwan’s folk beliefs also have many Japanese elements
台湾の民間信仰にも日本的な要素が多いのは、この理由ではないかと思う人も多いでしょう。
Is it because of the influence of Japanese colonial rule until today?
現在に至るまでの日本の植民地支配の影響でしょうか？
there are other wines
他のワインもあります
Or use this to let us know a little more about the history of Taiwan
または、台湾の歴史についてもう少し詳しく知るためにこれを使用してください
social reality
社会的現実
First I thought I should explain folk beliefs
まず民間信仰について説明しようと思いました
It's an academic term
学術用語です
In my definition this is an academic term
私の定義では、これは学術用語です
I am not sure if this term was used in China in the 1930s because it was influenced by Japan
この用語が日本の影響を受けて 1930 年代に中国で使用されたかどうかはわかりません。
Or take it from the Japanese academic circles and use it
あるいは日本の学界から抜粋して使用してください
Because many modern Chinese nouns come from Japanese
現代中国語の名詞の多くは日本語から来ているので、
For example, everyone knows that economics and philosophy
たとえば、経済学や哲学については誰もが知っています。
This is all Japanese translation from English to Kanji
これは英語から漢字へのすべての日本語訳です
Then China took it directly and used it
その後、中国はそれを直接取得して使用しました
So I have a little doubt, but I haven't done detailed research
少し疑問があるのですが、詳しく調べたわけではありません
Simply put, folk beliefs are generally used in this way in mainland China and Taiwan.
簡単に言えば、中国大陸や台湾では民間信仰が一般的にこのように使われています。
In some places it is called folk religion
地方によっては民間宗教と呼ばれることもある
The main meaning of folk belief in Taiwan refers to the belief in ghosts and gods
台湾の民間信仰の主な意味は、幽霊や神への信仰を指します。
However, there are some miscellaneous parts in it that first worship and follow the world.
しかし、その中には、まず世を崇拝し、従うという雑な部分もあります。
Tomorrow's belief itself does not have too many institutional religious rituals and scriptures
明日の信仰自体には、組織的な宗教儀式や経典があまりありません
or not at all
あるいは全くそうではない
Systematic rituals and classics
体系化された儀式と古典
where an institutional religion is necessary
組織的な宗教が必要な場合
but tomorrow faith does not
しかし明日の信仰はそうではありません
when he needs the ritual
彼が儀式を必要とするとき
When classics are needed, he intervenes in a teaching
古典が必要なときは、彼は授業に介入する
So if you go to temples in various places in Taiwan to see
台湾各地のお寺に行ってみると、
Often seen in the temple of what we call Tomorrow's Faith
私たちが「明日の信仰」と呼ぶ寺院でよく見られます。
There will be a member of the Taoist Association of the Republic of China hanging on his door
彼のドアには中華民国道教協会の会員がぶら下がっているでしょう
He said he was a Taoist
彼は自分は道士だと言いました
In fact, Taoism was one of the institutional religions in the past.
実際、道教は過去に組織された宗教の一つでした。
Taoism has its own rituals and scriptures
道教には独自の儀式と経典があります
Tomorrow belief in Taiwan is mainly involved in Taoist classics
台湾の明日信仰は主に道教の古典に関係している
When various religious ceremonies are required
各種宗教儀式が必要な場合
In fact, Taoism in Taiwan does not have its own public relations
実際、台湾の道教には独自の広報活動がありません。
That is to say, the public temple
つまり、公立寺院です。
Because Taoism in Taiwan is mainly righteous
台湾の道教は正義が中心なので
He always set up groups at home
彼はいつも家でグループを作ります
Then go out to do errands, go out to pick up cases
それから用事を済ませに出かけたり、ケースを受け取りに出かけたり
It can be said that more than 90% of Taiwan's Taoism survives on folk beliefs
台湾の道教の9割以上は民間信仰で残っていると言える
If everyone doesn't do it, don't do it another time
みんながやらないなら、次もやらないで
That Taoist temple will all be closed
その道教寺院はすべて閉鎖されるでしょう
So this is a cross talk relationship
これはクロストーク関係です
but they
だけどあの人達
You still can't say folk belief is Taoism
民間信仰はまだ道教とは言えない
In terms of what we're really working on defining
私たちが実際に何を定義しようとしているのかという点では、
There's still a big difference between the two
両者の間にはまだ大きな違いがある
I think folk beliefs are in the daily life of ordinary people in Taiwan society
民間信仰は台湾社会の庶民の日常生活の中にあると思います
If we want to talk about various religions
さまざまな宗教について話したい場合
we can't say it's called a believer
それを信者とは言えません
because it's not very strict
あまり厳密ではないので
can be defined as a believer
信者として定義できる
But it is the religion that participates in the most religious activities
しかし、最も多くの宗教活動に参加しているのは宗教です
It is folk belief with the largest population
人口が最も多い民間信仰です
Taiwan's folk beliefs are of course mainly derived from the bright moon
台湾の民間信仰は、もちろん主に明るい月に由来しています。
This Japanese memory we are going to talk about today
今日お話しするこの日本の記憶について
There are two main levels
主要なレベルは 2 つあります
one is
一つは
Taiwanese folk opera
台湾民俗オペラ
Worship many Japanese gods
多くの日本の神様を崇拝する
Where did this Japanese god come from?
この日本の神様はどこから来たのでしょうか？
why do you want to worship
なぜ礼拝したいのですか
This is what I want to introduce to you today
今日ご紹介したいのはこちら
give some examples
いくつか例を挙げてください
most
大部分
so far we
これまでのところ私たちは
Examples I can understand
私が理解できる例
another one is
もう一つは
Japanese style head
日本式的陣頭
About the team performing at the temple fair
縁日出演チームについて
it's japan
それは日本です
categorized
分類された
Japanese form
日本語の形
There has been a trend in recent years
近年ある傾向にある
But in fact in truly representative
しかし実際には本当に代表的なのは
from a long time ago
昔から
why is there such
なぜそんなものがあるのか
and
と
From five days to now
5日から今日まで
even
平
Not only did not decline
断らなかっただけではなく
and more and more
そしてますます
what is that
それは何ですか
what could be the reason
何が原因でしょうか
It's what I want to introduce to you today
今日紹介したいのはこれです
This post-famous
このポスト有名な
will be clean
きれいになります
The topic to be talked about
についてのトピック
Because generally we can easily think of saying
なぜなら、一般的に私たちはこう言うことを簡単に考えることができるからです。
you hear very serious japanese memories
とても深刻な日本の思い出が聞こえてきますね
Is it a result of colonial rule?
植民地支配の影響でしょうか？
Or does he have other factors that can explain it?
それとも彼にはそれを説明できる他の要因があるのでしょうか？
Although all our Japanese memories
私たちの日本の思い出はすべて
In the area of ​​Japanese gods
日本の神様の領域で
It seems to be related to Japan
日本にも関係があるようです
But in fact, the Japanese gods worshiped in Taiwanese temples
しかし実際には、日本の神々は台湾の寺院で崇拝されていました。
Japanese gods worshiped at Japanese shrines
日本の神社で祀られている日本の神様
How to pray, the form, the ritual and the meaning are completely different
祈り方も形も儀式も意味も全く違う
In fact, it was invented by Taiwan itself.
実は台湾自身が発明したものです。
How to worship this Japanese
この日本人をどう崇拝するか
Or will it eventually be integrated into the Chinese-style mid-range series?
それとも最終的には中華風のミッドレンジシリーズに統合されるのでしょうか？
So he looks like he has something to do with Japan
どうやら彼は日本と関係があるようだ
But in fact, his essence is still Chinese
しかし実際のところ、彼の本質は依然として中国人です
or Taiwanese, mostly Taiwanese
または台湾人、主に台湾人
not necessarily chinese
必ずしも中国人ではない
Because Japanese gods are not worshiped in China
中国では日本の神様は崇められていないから
In mainland China, even in Yuanxiang
中国本土でも、元祥でも
I started worshiping after I came to Taiwan
台湾に来てから参拝を始めました
There must be a special reason for him
彼には特別な理由があるに違いない
So I want to take this opportunity to introduce to you
そこでこの機会にぜひご紹介したいと思います
how did he get here
彼はどうやってここに来たの
Does he have any evolutionary history?
彼には進化の歴史があるのでしょうか？
or what's the point
それとも何の意味があるのですか
Well, if such an element appears in Taiwan's Tomorrow Antenna
まあ台湾の明日アンテナにそんな要素が出てきたら
Is it the legacy of having had enough of Japan's responsible rule?
日本の責任ある統治にうんざりした名残でしょうか？
In other words, this kind of culture continues to influence related
言い換えれば、この種の文化は関連する文化に影響を与え続けているということです。
This is a topic I want to answer today
今日はこれに答えたいテーマです
Of course what I report is what I see
もちろん、私が報告するものは私が見ているものです
what i understand
私が理解していること
for your reference
ご参考に
This is not a standard answer
これは標準的な答えではありません
Let's start by explaining
まずは説明から始めましょう
I said
私は言いました
memory of japan
日本記憶
That is, Japanese elements are in Chinese teaching, in Taiwan Chinese teaching
つまり、中国語の教育には日本の要素があり、台湾の中国語の教育には日本の要素が含まれています。
In fact, before the war
実は戦前
just before the end of the war
終戦直前
A former shrine in Taiwan
台湾のかつての神社
is so irrelevant
とても無関係です
When I was a Japanese student, I actually worked very hard.
私は日本の学生だった頃、本当に一生懸命勉強しました。
to push
プッシュする
shrine
神社
Taiwan used to have about 200
台湾にはかつて約200人がいた
More than 200 shrines
200以上の神社
Among them are shrines of various ranks managed by the government system
中には官制により管理される様々なランクの神社もある
at least sixty-eight
少なくとも68人
Of course, everyone knows that the biggest one is Yuanshan.
もちろん、最大のものは圓山であることは誰もが知っています。
Now Yuanshan Hotel used to be called Taiwan Shrine
現在の圓山飯店は以前は台湾神社と呼ばれていました
Or Shenge or Taiwan Shrine
または神華または台湾神社
That is equivalent to the land farm level
これは陸上農場レベルに相当します
Then there are national
それから国立もある
it has many levels
多くのレベルがあります
these shrines
これらの神社
After the war, most of them were changed into Zhongli poems
戦後、そのほとんどが中礼詩に変えられた
Or lovesickness naturally
あるいは自然に病気が好きになる
late in the war
戦争後期
Apart from the ring-illumination movement
リングを外す動作とは別に
ask home
家に尋ねる
The original God tanks in your home cannot carry Ancestors
あなたの家の元のゴッドタンクは先祖を運ぶことができません
Can't bring gods
神様は連れていけない
Also bring Japanese gods
日本の神様も連れてくる
so thunderbolt
サンダーボルト
At that time, the idols were not burned
当時、偶像は焼かれませんでした
just to hide
ただ隠すためだけに
And as the war progressed
そして戦争が進むにつれて
for
ために
The people, the general manager, and the government must invite teachers and students from public schools to visit the shrine collectively, visit the shrine on a regular basis, and examine
国民、総務、政府は、公立学校の教師と生徒を一斉に参拝させ、定期的に参拝し、検証しなければならない。
This was probably in the 1940s, late in the war, it was obvious
これはおそらく 1940 年代、戦争末期に明らかになりました。
After such strong indoctrination, we can count from Huang Minhua in 1935
このような強力な教化の後、1935 年の黄敏華から数えることができます。
For at least 10 years until 1945, Japan vigorously promoted or instilled rituals such as Japanese Shinto shrines in Taiwanese society.
1945 年までの少なくとも 10 年間、日本は台湾社会に日本の神社などの儀式を精力的に奨励または浸透させました。
After 10 years of practice or nurturing, once the war is over, there will be nothing for a lifetime
10年間練習や育成をしても、戦争が終われば一生何も残らない
All the Japanese shrine elements in the home are now gone after the relationship
交際後、家の中にある日本の神社の要素はすべてなくなりました。
First, I ran to a certain black house, and the god that people worshiped came out again immediately
まず、とある黒い家に駆け込むと、人々が崇拝する神がすぐにまた出てきた
Gao Se is completely withdrawn from Taiwan
高世氏は台湾から完全撤退
I'm not exaggerating when I say something wrong
間違ったことを言うのは誇張ではありません
But Taiwan is now visible
でも台湾が見えてきました
This is the only relatively complete look in Taiwan.
これは台湾で唯一比較的完全な外観です。
Possibly outside Japan
もしかしたら日本国外かもしれない
Keep the best look in the world
世界で最高の外観を維持する
This look was built in 1938
この外観は 1938 年に建てられました
It's called Taoyuan Look
それは桃園ルックと呼ばれています
Hsinchu Central Taoyuan
新竹中央桃園
Covered look of a present set
プレゼントセットのカバーされた外観
This is the official look
これが正式な見た目です
This is Torii
鳥居です
Torii usually have two floors
鳥居は通常2階建てです
I think you have been to Japan
あなたは日本に行ったことがあると思います
I have seen the news of the look
ルックのニュースを見ました
There were originally five torii gates
元々は五つの鳥居があったそうです
ginseng rice in japan
日本の高麗人参ご飯
going to look
見に行きます
usually noisy with the road every day
通常、毎日道路で騒がしいです
There will be several torii gates
鳥居がいくつかあります
At the same time, there were originally five
同時に、もともとは5つありました
There are four because the road is too wide
道が広いので4つあります
etc.
等
At the same time dance only this one
同時にこれだけ踊って
And it is cut into double ten
そしてそれはダブルテンにカットされます
Originally two layers
元々は二層
Become a double ten shape
ダブルテンの形になる
Everyone, if you have been to Tainan's original Juwang Pond
台南の元祖朱王池に行ったことのある皆さん
There is also a similar double pool
同様の二重プールもあります
It turned out to be a torii
鳥居だったことが判明
It was also renovated to become a double pool now
こちらも改装されてダブルプールになりました
Then Bai Chongxi put the words on it
それから白崇熙がそれに言葉を加えました
This is the worship of the shrine
これが神社の参拝です
reservation would be good
予約が良いでしょう
In 1972
1972年
Because Taiwan broke off diplomatic relations with Japan
台湾が日本と国交を断絶したため
was supposed to clear all
全てクリアするはずだった
Express Japanese nationalism
日本のナショナリズムを表現する
Music Sensation Colonial Remnants
ミュージック センセーション コロニアル レムナント
Don't know why this Taiwanese shrine
なぜこの台湾の神社なのか分かりません
did not dismantle
解体しなかった
Maybe it's because Taiwan
台湾だからかな
the sea is well preserved
海はよく保存されています
Because most of the shrines were built after the war
神社の多くは戦後に建てられたものなので、
was changed to
に変更されました
Almost all of them are changed to middle words
ほぼすべてが中単語に変更されます
Japanese period shrine
日本時代的神社
Originally, there were quite a few words in the middle list
もともと、真ん中のリストにはかなりの数の単語がありました
It is to pay homage to these Japanese foreign wars
これらの日本の対外戦争に敬意を表するためです
or died in the line of duty
または職務中に死亡した
Mainly military and police personnel
主に軍人や警察関係者
There is a Chinese word next to this Wonsan Hotel
この元山ホテルの隣には中国語の文字があります
That place turned out to be what they called Zhengguo Shrine
その場所は正国神社と呼ばれるものだった
It is dedicated to paying homage to Japanese soldiers who died in battle
戦いで亡くなった日本兵を追悼するために捧げられています
Of course it also includes the assumption that there are Taiwanese there
もちろん台湾人がいるという前提も含まれます
Later that was changed to the middle word
その後、それは中間の単語に変更されました
Ability to refurb heavy cover
厚いカバーを再生する能力
Who was the Taoyuan Shrine that was not deleted?
削除されなかった桃園神社とは誰なのか？
It should also be because he changed it to a middle word
それも中言葉に変えたからでしょうね
And his buildings are preserved in this way to make people complete
そして彼の建物は人々を完成させるためにこのように保存されています
Originally in 1980
もともとは1980年に
The Taiwan county government feels that this shrine is a bit dilapidated
台湾県政府はこの神社が少し荒廃していると感じている
Decided to dismantle it and replace it with a new one
分解して新しいものに交換することにしました
Already dispatched
すでに発送済み
that race is over
そのレースは終わった
The architect who won the bid is going to see the site
落札した建築家が現場を見に行く
How can such a good architect be demolished?
これほど優れた建築家をどうやって取り壊すことができるのでしょうか？
So after 1985
それで 1985 年以降
At that time, Taiwanese society was more accepting.
当時、台湾社会はもっと受け入れられていました。
Use the concept of cultural assets to look at such buildings
文化財という概念で建物を見てみよう
So not only is there no difference
したがって、違いがないだけではなく、
And asked the government to grant money to renovate
そして政府に改修のための資金援助を要請した
So in 1994 he became a tertiary stock fund
そこで 1994 年に彼は第三次株式ファンドになりました。
Well, Taiwan in recent years
さて、近年の台湾
past two years
過去2年間
Suddenly added two new shrines
突如として新たな神社が2つ追加
This shrine is very small, in fact, it looks like a shrine
この神社はとても小さいですが、実際には神社のように見えます
But he's interesting
でも彼は面白いです
he is this place
彼はここです
The Wudanshe Incident in Pingtung in 1874
1874年に屏東で起きた五丹社事件
It's just an excuse from Japan
それは日本の言い訳に過ぎない
Lu Xiong has been killed by this surrogate in Taiwan
盧雄氏は台湾でこの代理母に殺害された
So send troops to visit and punish Taiwan
だから軍隊を派遣して台湾を訪問し懲罰せよ
That's why it's called the Wudanshe Incident, in 1874
1874年に起きたこの事件が「五丹社事件」と呼ばれるのはそのためです。
The place where it happened is the Buddhist Temple in Gaoshi
事件が起きた場所は高市の仏教寺院です
The shrine acquired by Takashi Buddhist Shrine the year before last
一昨年に崇仏神社が取得した神社
a Japanese priest
日本の僧侶
In order to thank him, he spent 10 million yen himself
感謝の気持ちを込めて自ら1000万円を費やした
In order to thank the Taiwanese people who suffered from the March 1 earthquake for their respect for Japan
3月1日の地震で被害を受けた台湾の人々の日本への敬意に感謝するため
so he made this shrine
それで彼はこの神社を作りました
Send to Gao Shi Buddhist Society
高師仏教協会に送る
The current Gaoshi Buddhist Society
現在の高師仏教会
all aborigines
すべての原住民
almost all christian
ほぼ全員がキリスト教徒
But they think this shrine is meaningful
しかし彼らはこの神社に意味があると考えている
He said it was from the Peony Society to the present
牡丹会から現在までとのこと。
The aborigines here in the Peony Society have feuded with Japan
ここ牡丹協会の原住民たちは日本と反目している
Hope this solves it
これで解決するといいですね
it means friendly
フレンドリーという意味です
I think this kind of explanation is also very meaningful
このような説明も非常に有意義だと思います
Well, the other shrine was just 60% the year before.
まあ、もう一つの神社は前年はちょうど60％でした。
This is a completely new shrine built on the old foundation
古い土台の上に建てられた全く新しい神社です
This is a torii. Standard torii.
こちらは鳥居です、スタンダードな鳥居です。
this is a small shrine
ここは小さな神社です
This shrine government is small
この神社庁は小さいです
Its face width is very small
顔の幅が非常に小さい
Japanese shrine
日本的神社
If you have been to Japan, you will know
日本に行ったことがある人ならわかると思いますが、
Except for that big store
あの大きな店を除いて
There will often be many small ones next to them
多くの場合、その隣に小さなものがたくさんあります
similar to what we say
私たちが言っていることと似ています
That is also a shrine
あれも神社ですよ
This kind of shrine is basically like this
この手の神社は基本的にこんな感じです
This was originally a Japanese immigrant village.
ここはもともと日系移民の村だったそうです。
It was originally called Routing Immigrant Village
元々はルーティング移民村と呼ばれていました
That
それか
why is this
なぜこれ
This is led by the county government
これは県政府が主導している
There is absolutely no religious reason for sightseeing
観光に宗教的な理由は全くありません
think we commanded the shrine
私たちが神社に命令したと思う
will attract more tourists
より多くの観光客を惹きつけるでしょう
Do you guys see why there is an incense burner next to it?
なぜ隣に香炉があるかわかりますか？
there is a gold furnace
金の炉があります
Because there is a temple next to it
隣にお寺があるので
This is the village temple
ここは村のお寺です
well, the story should start here
さて、物語はここから始まるはずです
this place
この場所
It turned out to be an old shrine
古い神社だったことが判明
its foundations are still
その基礎はまだ残っています
it's all falling
それはすべて落ちています
just started after the war
戦後始まったばかりの
This is for everyone video immigrant village
これはみんなのビデオです 移民村
Japanese usually go back
日本人は大抵帰ってしまう
The original Taiwanese outside the immigrant village
移民村の外にいる本来の台湾人
basically Han Chinese
基本的に漢民族
just come in
ただ入ってください
And then there were successive
そして、次々と出てきたのが、
Residents from felt immigrant homes and other places sign in
フェルト移民の家やその他の場所の住民がサインインする
So the population of this village is increasing
それでこの村の人口は増えています
A place with only population needs goodbye
人口だけの場所には別れが必要だ
need goodbye
さよならが必要です
First of all usually if there is no god
まず通常、神がいない場合
worship the land
土地を崇拝する
it's normal
それは普通です
So in the beginning we put that
それで最初にそれを入れました
At that time the shrine was broken
その時神社は壊れた
right on top of this foundation
この基礎の上に
Take a simple one to worship the Lord of the Earth
地球の主を崇拝するためにシンプルなものを選んでください
Later the population increased
その後人口が増えた
more and more gods
神様がどんどん増えていく
Because people everywhere depend on
世界中の人々が依存しているからです
Bring their gods too
彼らの神も連れて来なさい
after goodbye
さよならの後
let them worship together
一緒に礼拝しましょう
Now they later built a temple called Kunchi Hall
その後、彼らはくんち堂と呼ばれる寺院を建てました。
I just saw a temple with a golden furnace
黄金の炉のある寺院を見たところです
because there are too many people
人が多すぎるので
It turns out that the Earth Temple is too small
地球の神殿は小さすぎることが判明
Therefore, the Kunchi Hall was built on the open space next to the Digong Temple of the God Society.
そこで、神社地公廟の隣の広場にくんち堂が建てられました。
After the completion of construction, the Temple of Earth God was abandoned.
建設完了後、地神の神殿は放棄されました。
I don't need it, so it's empty there
要らないから空いてるよ
so now we have the chance to bring it back
だから今、それを取り戻すチャンスがある
Put another one on the front
もう一つを前に置きます
Shrine built for sightseeing tour
観光ツアーのために建てられた神社
This is a shrine
ここは神社です
This foundation is the volume of the steps of the shrine in the old immigrant village era in the Japanese era
この基礎は日本時代の旧移民村時代の神社の階段のボリュームです
That above now see these are new
以上で、これらが新しいことがわかりました
These lights should be new too.
これらのライトも新しいはずです。
That's about as far as I know
私の知る限りではそれくらいです
Taiwan has relatively complete shrines, old and new
台湾には古いものから新しいものまで比較的充実した神社があります
You may also see
あなたも見るかもしれません
There are remains of shrines, but they are all incomplete
神社の遺跡はあるが、いずれも未完成である
If you have the opportunity to go to Taiwan
台湾に行く機会があれば
this
これ
zero department store
零百貨
On the top of the roof of Zero Department Store
ゼロデパートの屋上で
There must be you as a shrine
神社としてあなたがいるはずです
that was back then
それは当時のことでした
The department store built its own shrine
デパートは独自の神社を建てた
do it there
そこでやってください
He still kept parts that weren't completely broken
彼は完全に壊れていない部品をまだ保管していた
good
良い
I will introduce next
次に紹介します
Japanese gods
日本の神様
There are quite a few Japanese gods in Taiwan
台湾には日本の神様がたくさんいる
What I will introduce to you later is to compare
後で紹介するのは比較です
It should be said that the more famous
より有名であると言うべきです
In fact there are a few more that I didn't include
実はここには載せていないものもいくつかあります
that but maybe smaller
それよりも小さいかもしれない
The earliest and most northern part I know is that Wugu has a nickname
私が知っている最古かつ最北の地域では、ウグーにはニックネームがあるということです
doing a japanese god
日本の神様をやっている
because north is south
北は南だから
the further south the more
南に行くほど
These Japanese gods have a characteristic
日本の神様には特徴がある
today
今日
was first
最初だった
probably since the 1920s
おそらく1920年代以来
ah
ああ
Japanese gods appear
日本の神様が登場
It is the Japanese who are worshiped as gods
神として崇められているのは日本人です
passed away
亡くなりました
until now more and more
今までもっともっと
They also have common characteristics
共通の特徴もあります
they all died
彼らは全員死んだ
just die badly
ただひどく死ぬだけ
suicide
自殺
killed in this war
この戦争で殺された
or accidental death
または事故死
All kinds of deaths are rarely normal
あらゆる種類の死が正常であることはめったにありません
These gods who became the gods of Japan
日本の神となった神々
mostly this way
ほとんどこの方法で
Especially in the later period, many of them are related to war
特に後期は戦争に関わるものが多い
Why is there a special emphasis on dying
なぜ死ぬことに特別な重点が置かれるのか
This is because in Taiwan the traditional
それは台湾では伝統的に
inside ghost priest
幽霊僧侶の中
dead person
死んだ人
if our own ancestors
もし私たち自身の祖先が
because someone worshiped
誰かが崇拝したから
So it's not a question of whether he becomes a ghost or not
だから彼が幽霊になるかどうかは問題ではない
but this
しかしこれは
If someone dies unexpectedly and no one worships him
誰かが突然亡くなり、誰も彼を崇拝しなくなった場合
is a ghost
幽霊です
and if he is
そして彼がそうなら
If you die, that will become a regulation
死んだらそれが規制になる
Well, if things like this are going to be messed up and come to celebrate birthdays, that would be very scary.
まあ、このままめちゃくちゃになって誕生日祝いに来られたら、それはそれで怖いですけどね。
So Taiwan is full of hidden palaces and temples
台湾には隠れた宮殿や寺院がたくさんあります
It's out of this fear, fear
それはこの恐れ、恐れから来ています
As you all know, China has a very famous god
皆さんご存知の通り、中国にはとても有名な神様がいます。
called sightseeing
観光という名の
Holy Land Army
聖地軍
Why so many people please be so holy
なぜこれほど多くの人がそんなに神聖であってください
In the first life, he also died of knowing
最初の人生では、彼もまた知って死んだ
You have to actually think about how sightseeing dies.
観光がどのようにして消滅するのかを実際に考えなければなりません。
If sightseeing becomes a ghost one day
いつか観光が幽霊になったら
And if he's going to fight, don't you think that's scary?
もし彼が戦うことになったら、それは怖いと思いませんか？
his power
彼の力
So I hurry up and make him a god
だから急いで彼を神にしてやる
The first Japanese to become a Japanese god was a Japanese policeman
日本人で初めて日本の神になったのは日本の警察官だった
He is also dead
彼も死んでいる
he is also himself
彼もまた彼自身である
suicide
自殺
But he is for
しかし、彼は賛成です
Avoid local people fighting for rights
権利を求めて争う地元住民を避ける
The result was stabbed
結果刺されました
he feels very
彼はとても感じています
he felt
彼はそう感じている
he was wronged
彼は不当な扱いを受けた
I feel very upset
とても動揺しています
so he killed himself
それで彼は自殺した
this
これ
Japanese police call wearing blue natural
日本の警察はブルーナチュラルを着て電話をかけます
in the locals
地元の人々の中で
Usually it is simply referred to as the Japanese Prince
通常は単に日本の皇子と呼ばれます。
why? because
なぜ?なぜなら
he attached
彼は付けた
Mr. Fu'an worshiped a bunch of gods
福安氏はたくさんの神々を崇拝していた
There is also a custom
習慣もあります
every october
毎年10月
will win the prince
王子に勝つだろう
Send off the prince
王子を見送って
will make a kingship
王権を作るだろう
burn him
彼を燃やす
Wang Chuanche is very simple and mainly made of paper
Wang Chuanche は非常にシンプルで、主に紙でできています。
so every year
だから毎年
there will be one in october
10月にもあるでしょう
The ceremony of sending off the prince
皇太子お見送りの儀式
That's because there are many gods
神様がたくさんいるから
many do not understand
多くの人は理解していません
Abbreviation
略語
after death
死後
no matter the japanese
日本人関係なく
or Chinese
または中国語
or Taiwanese
または台湾人
or become a god
あるいは神になるか
usually
いつもの
It is related to this miraculous deed
それはこの奇跡的な行為に関係しています
absolutely not without reason
絶対に理由がないわけではない
if it doesn't work
それがうまくいかない場合
There must be a supernatural
超自然的なものがあるに違いない
or weirdness
あるいは奇妙さ
The most common statement is
最も一般的なステートメントは次のとおりです
someone died somewhere
誰かがどこかで死んだ
And then a few years later
そして数年後
start ghosting
ゴースティングを開始する
say last night
昨夜言う
i saw a person
人を見ました
riding a white horse
白い馬に乗って
ready to go
準備過去
A few days later another person said
数日後、別の人がこう言いました
yes i saw it too
はい、私も見ました
I spread more and more
どんどん広がっていきました
everyone starts to fear
誰もが恐れ始める
just remembered to say
言うことを思い出しただけ
Because that place was many years ago
そこは何年も前の場所だったから
there was a murder
殺人事件があった
one person died at the scene
現場で1人が死亡した
go with them
彼らと一緒に行きます
build a small temple
蓋一個小廟
do him
彼にやれ
just balance
ただバランスを取るだけ
Most of them have Yingong Temple
それらのほとんどにはインゴン寺院があります
that's how it came
それがこうして来た
or
また
this
これ
Probably only Yiaigong Japanese gods
おそらくイアイゴンの日本の神様だけでしょう
Although he died in a coma
彼は昏睡状態で亡くなったものの、
But he doesn't belong to the Faith of Pregnancy
しかし彼は妊娠の信仰に属していません
The Japanese we are talking about here
ここで話している日本人とは
Almost all Japanese gods are part of the belief in pregnancy
ほとんどすべての日本の神様は妊娠信仰の一部です
Pregnant
妊娠中
let's look at this first
まずはこれを見てみましょう
This Fu'an Gong was only completed in the first two years
この福安功の最初の2年間は完了しました。
He has a ton of gods in his hall
彼のホールにはたくさんの神々がいます
There are about 50 statues
像は約50体あります
There is only one statue named Yi Ai Gong
イ・アイ・ゴンという名前の像は1つだけです
because he asked wrong
彼は間違った質問をしたから
Which one is Yi Ai Gong?
イー・アイ・ゴンはどれですか？
Therefore, for the convenience of energy out of position, give him a brand name
したがって、エネルギーの転位の便宜のために、彼にブランド名を付けます
put a name tag
名札を付ける
The other gods have no names
他の神々には名前がありません
only love public
公共だけを愛する
because he is very famous
彼はとても有名なので
And because it started in 1920
そしてそれは1920年に始まったので、
Later, a lot of Fu Lai
その後、フーライがたくさん
This is the seaside is relatively poor
ここは海辺が比較的貧弱です
Later many immigrants
その後、多くの移民が
So separate out the accidental ones
したがって、偶発的なものは分離してください
So when there were the most in Taiwan, there were real temples worshiping this accidental public.
したがって、台湾に最も多くの寺院があったとき、この偶然の大衆を崇拝する本物の寺院がありました。
Some are ancestral gods, some are northern gods
祖先の神もいるし、北方の神もいる
Mostly local residents
地元住民がほとんど
Most of them are in Chiayi
そのほとんどは嘉義にあります
The farthest one is in Xinzhuang
一番遠いのは新荘にある
There is a temple in Xinzhuang
新荘にはお寺があります
It's called Beixun Sheng'an Palace
北峻聖安宮といいます。
when they were in 2000
彼らが2000年の頃
because this
なぜならこれは
accident office
意外公室
They are from Yokobe, so they go to Kanagawa Prefecture
横部出身なので神奈川県に行くそうです。
Looking for my grandfather's hometown
祖父の故郷を探して
go help him
彼を助けに行ってください
Received by this of Kanagawa Prefecture
神奈川県のこちらから頂きました
very grand reception
とても盛大なレセプション
Just built in 2014
2014年に建てられたばかり
This one was built in 2014
こちらは2014年に建てられたものです
in front of the temple on the right
神社前右側
made a
を作りました
Embossed story wall
エンボス加工のストーリーウォール
It's just telling the story of the accident
事故の話をしているだけだ
Now the selling point of Fu Angong
さてフーアンゴンのセールスポイント
everyone is still asking this
誰もがまだこれを尋ねています
Lang Weizun
ラング・ウェイズン
so they just stay here
だから彼らはただここに居るだけ
made a story wall
ストーリーウォールを作りました
They know this is what everyone is interested in now
彼らは今、誰もがこれに興味を持っていることを知っています
So the status of Yi Ai Palace
では、イアイパレスの状況は
more and more winning
越來越勝
well gateway say all these japanese gods almost
まあ、ゲートウェイはこれらすべての日本の神々をほぼ言うでしょう
They are all part of Yingong's faith
それらはすべてインゴンの信仰の一部です
There are Yingong beliefs are
インゴン信仰があります
At least in the Mingyue area, there used to be
少なくとも明月地域では以前は
But how popular is Taiwan
それにしても台湾って人気あるんですね
Why Taiwan is so popular
台湾が人気の理由
because of Taiwan
台湾のせいで
this
これ
special environment
特殊的環境
There are many natural disasters in this Israeli society
このイスラエル社会には自然災害がたくさんあります
so-called fighting spirit
いわゆる闘争心
For example, what are the most natural disasters in Taiwan?
たとえば、台湾で最も多い自然災害は何ですか?
You may think of an earthquake
地震を思い浮かべるかもしれません
earthquake
地震
It's been a long time since this severe earthquake
この大地震から長い時間が経ちました
But every year there are
しかし、毎年あるのは、
in the previous era
前の時代に
disaster is easy
災害は簡単だ
this happens
これが起こる
It's just that the family and life are gone.
ただ、家族と命がなくなってしまっただけなのです。
In addition, Taiwan has many
また、台湾にはたくさんの
Luo Han Ka
ルオ・ハン・カー
but come on
でもさあ
In fact, it can't be sucked
実際には吸い込めない
Can't take extra coupons
追加のクーポンは受け取れません
And of course alone
そしてもちろん一人でも
may come by accident or poverty
事故や貧困によって起こるかもしれない
starved to death in the countryside
田舎で餓死した
i was found one day
私はある日見つけられました
There's a lot of bitterness left
苦みがかなり残っている
That's because there are many natural disasters
自然災害が多いからね
so often
しばしば
There is a saying called chasing interest
興味を追うという言葉があります
where the collar will find a dead body
首輪が死体を発見する場所
whatever the reason
理由が何であれ
then i found this
それから私はこれを見つけました
common man criminal
一般人犯罪者
must hurry to bury him
急いで彼を埋葬しなければならない
after burial
埋葬後
buried well
よく埋もれた
and because he didn't know
そして彼は知らなかったので
what is his history
彼の経歴は何ですか
don't know how he died
彼がどうやって死んだのか分からない
So it's best to do it for him
だから彼のためにそうするのが一番いいよ
If you don't feel comfortable
快適でない場合は
lazy again
また怠け者
what else
ほかに何か
Just build a small temple
小さな神殿を建てるだけ
just start
ただ始めてください
Then a Yongyin Temple appeared
すると龍陰寺が現れた
So the number of Yongyin Temples in Taiwan
ということで、台湾の龍陰寺の数は
Much
非常多
and very common
そして非常に一般的な
preferably
好ましい
Then worship and become a god
そして崇拝して神になろう
I can bless you after becoming a god
神になったら祝福できるよ
keep bless us
私たちを祝福してください
keep smoking
喫煙を続ける
and can even get you this
そしてこれを手に入れることもできます
Get rich
裕福になる
That
それか
these japanese gods
この日本の神々
almost
ほとんど
public faith
公的な信仰
part of form
形態的一環
good
良い
this is
これは
closer to us
私たちの近くに
Hsinchu Orchid has a small temple
新竹蘭には小さなお寺があります
Holy Army
聖軍
what's in here
ここには何が入っていますか
this is japan
ここは日本です
everyone see
誰もが見る
Japanese style clothing
和装
this is the original
これがオリジナルです
stone bow
石の弓
means land bow
陸の弓を意味します
This is a soldier from Taiwan who went to fight in Nanyang
これは南陽に出征した台湾の兵士です
after the war died
戦争が終わった後
returned ashes
返された遺骨
also put here
ここにも置きます
So there are several elements
ということで、いくつかの要素があります
will be added together
一緒に追加されます
They built a sanctuary
彼らは聖域を建てた
bring these
これらを持ってきてください
It is a temple with Yin Gong
陰功のある寺院です
Because the person who brought it is God
持ってきた人は神様だから
And this why there are Japanese soldiers
そしてこれが日本兵がいる理由です
here
ここ
The war will start because he is close to Hsinchu House Airport
新竹家空港に近いから戦争が始まる
U.S. bombing
米軍の爆撃
Japanese soldiers working there were killed
そこで働いていた日本兵が死亡した
It's nearby, so they locals take that
近くにあるので、地元の人がそれを利用します
Collect the body and bury it here, after the burial
埋葬後、遺体を回収してここに埋葬します
Let him do the tax, so build a small temple to handle it
税金は彼にやらせて、それを処理するために小さな寺院を建ててください
Then this original
じゃあこのオリジナルは
The boulders worshiped by the Hakka people are also included
客家の人々が崇拝していた巨石も含まれる
this is later
これは後で
After being put together, one day next to this small temple
組み立てられて、いつかこの小さなお寺の隣に
There is a private person who is rich, and his family worships
裕福な個人がいて、彼の家族が崇拝している
Mother Chitose
母ちとせ
He doesn't know why he developed, and then he built a big temple called
彼はなぜ自分が発展したのか分かりませんが、その後、と呼ばれる大きな寺院を建てました。
Dai Tianfu came to worship his loving mother Qiansui
戴天福は愛する母乾水を崇拝するために来た
Therefore, a relatively large temple was built next to the Holy Army Hall
そのため、聖軍殿の隣に比較的大きな神殿が建てられました。
Let’s just say that you, Yungong Temple, are all too low-level.
言っておきますが、雲公寺はレベルが低すぎます。
Ours is a loving mother, Chitose is a prince
うちは優しいお母さん、千歳は王子様
So you are in the Regulatory Affairs Hall, so this Holy Army Hall
それで、あなたは規制問題ホールにいるので、この聖軍ホール
It became an affiliated temple of Dai Tianfu
大天府の末寺となる
The planning hall, the current shape has become like this
企画館、現在の形はこんな感じになりました
This is Zhengpuxiang, Chiayi County, there is a village called Shengkeng Village
ここは嘉義県正浦郷、盛坑村という村があります
He has a village temple called Kaifenggong, and the temple on Xuannan Island
彼は開封宮という村の寺院と玄南島の寺院を持っています。
He worships five thousand years old, you nest for two or two days, even the Holy Mother and so on
彼は5000歳を崇拝し、あなたは2日か2日間巣を作り、聖母さえも崇拝します。
The most special thing is that there is a temple called Zhongying in the left front of their temple.
最も特別なことは、彼らの寺院の左手前に中営という寺院があることです。
Generally, temples in Taiwan have a concept called five battalions of soldiers and horses to protect this sacred space.
一般的に台湾の寺院には、この神聖な空間を守るために兵馬五大隊という概念があります。
Our real personnel, whether it is the police or the army, bless you for the peace of this area
警察であれ軍隊であれ、私たちの本物の職員がこの地域の平和を祝福します
In the sacred space, in the space of the gods, there is a similar concept
神聖な空間、神の空間にも同様の概念があります
So there are five battalions defending the village
つまり、村を守るのは 5 つの大隊です
To put it simply, there used to be many temples, a village temple, he had his sphere of influence called sacrificial village
簡単に言うと、かつては寺が多く、村の寺があり、犠牲の村と呼ばれる勢力範囲を持っていた。
The meaning of sacrificial village is that the god of this temple is going to celebrate his birthday, and if everyone wants to pay, he will pay the money
犠牲の村の意味は、この寺院の神様が誕生日を祝う予定で、みんながお金を払いたければお金を払うという意味です。
good top
良いトップ
So what good do you have?
それで、どんな良いことがありますか？
statement to protect you
あなたを守るための声明
this is your benefit
これはあなたの利益です
You can invite the gods back to your home to do it
神々を家に招いてそうしてもらうことができます
you have this right
あなたにはその権利があります
but to act
しかし行動すること
bye bye
バイバイ
Everyone wants to pay together
みんな一緒に支払いたい
you have to donate
寄付しなければなりません
That's called sacrificial power
それを犠牲力という
Simply put, this is called sacrificial power
簡単に言えば、これを犠牲的な力と呼びます
The sacrificial right belongs to the god hall of this village temple
生贄の権利はこの村の寺院の神殿にある
How does he rule? How does he protect An Ming?
彼はどのように統治し、どのようにして安明を守るのでしょうか?
so he wants me five soldiers
それで彼は私に5人の兵士を望んでいる
doesn't matter
無所謂
So East, West, North, South, Middle
つまり東、西、北、南、中
This is an imitation of traditional Chinese military concepts
これは伝統的な中国軍を模倣するというコンセプトです
Usually the middle camp is the most important
通常中營最重要
Because Zhongying is in the middle of the village
中営は村の真ん中にあるので
or temple gate
または山門
Zhongying is the most important
中營最重要
What is Yuansai in Zhongying?
中営の元祭とは何ですか？
Si San sent envoys
シサンは使者を送った
Elements of Zhongtan
中丹の要素
Lee Roger
リー・ロジャー
Generally, the middle camp looks like this
大体中陣営はこんな感じ
As a result, the middle camp of this temple
その結果、この寺院の中陣営は、
Zhongtan Yuansai is called Ice General Palace
中潭元斎は氷将軍宮と呼ばれる
is a japanese
日本人です
so you see there's a japanese flag hanging here
ここに日の丸が掲げられているのがわかりますか
inside inside
内側 内側
because of this place
この場所のせいで
Japan's era
日本の時代
There used to be soldiers and police who came here to block and steal
昔はここに兵士や警察が来て、妨害したり盗んだりしていました
Many people died here
ここで多くの人が亡くなった
So the local people put these dead local people
それで地元の人々はこれらの死んだ地元の人々を置きま​​した
offer up
申し出る
put one of them
そのうちの1つを置きます
recruited as a soldier
兵士として採用された
become a substitute
代わりになる
This Nakato Motosuan
この中戸本水庵
be here
ここに
In charge of soldiers and horses
主管兵馬的
This is the only one in Taiwan
台湾ではここだけです
Nakato Moto I have seen is considered a foreigner
私が見たナカト・モトは外国人だと思われます
across this
この向こう側
just that temple
ちょうどその寺院
The village next door is called the Three Layer Village
隣の村は三層村と呼ばれています
Between these two villages there is a tax declaration
これら 2 つの村の間には税金の申告があります
called a three-tier tax return
三段階納税申告書と呼ばれる
a tax crossing
税金の交差点
there is a land cemetery
土地の墓地があります
prisoner of war palace
捕虜宮殿
this is earth palace
ここは地球の宮殿です
this is it
これだよ
Another Japanese soldier
もう一人の日本兵
In fact, it is the same as the current one
実は現行品と同じです
The same series of Kaifeng workers are actually local
開封の同じ一連の労働者は実際には地元の人です
that is, the same area
つまり同じエリアです
The two villages worship their own
2 つの村はそれぞれの村を崇拝します
But it's actually the same thing that happens
しかし、実際に起こっているのと同じことです
Okay, here we are at Yile Military
さて、ここはイイル軍です
real military operations happen to soldiers
実際の軍事作戦は兵士たちに起こる
make rotten then become god
腐らせてから神になる
in Taiwan's history
台湾の歴史の中で
There are two big events
大きなイベントが２つあります
One is about Japan
一つは日本についてです
One is 1895
一つは1895年
When Japan comes to take over and rule Taiwan
日本が台湾を占領し統治するとき
because of some confrontation
何らかの対立のせいで
Military action against the people of Taiwan
台湾国民に対する軍事行動
So of course people will die
だから当然人は死ぬ
Of course Taiwanese die more
もちろん台湾人はもっと死ぬ
japanese die very little
日本人は死ぬ人が少ない
Japanese soldiers also suffered losses
日本兵也有損失
these dead somewhere
これらはどこかで死んでいる
I often hear that a person died in that place
そこで人が亡くなったという話をよく聞きます
japanese officer japanese soldier
日本軍官 日本軍人
Then afraid of him making trouble
それから彼が問題を起こすのが怖い
so start him
それで彼を始めます
Many Japanese lives are born in this way
多くの日本人の命はこうして生まれます
so
それで
See Tamiya without this
これなしのタミヤを参照してください
And after he took his feet, he automatically
そして彼が立ち上がった後、彼は自動的に
upgraded to become
になるようにアップグレードされました
say he is this
彼はこれだと言う
he is already a thousand years old
彼はもう千歳だ
netizen class
ネチズンクラス
And he also said that his surname is Zhu Mingzheng, which of course is what Ji Tong said.
そして、自分の姓は朱明正であるとも言いましたが、もちろんこれは季通が言ったことです。
The Keeton that Keeton is going to talk about
キートンが話そうとしているキートン
The Japanese don't know why there is a Chinese-style name
なぜ中国風の名前が付いているのか日本人には分からない
Keeton said to probably send it off.
キートンはおそらく見送るだろうと言いました。
The inscription in the temple is sent like this
寺院の碑文はこのように送られます
This is
これは
There is a small temple in Xigang Zeng Wenxi Local Monument
西崗曾文渓郷土碑には小さな寺院があります
Looking at the stele, you will know that this is the county of Yongyun Palace
石碑を見ると、ここが龍雲宮の郡であることがわかります。
Inside worship three Japanese pilots
内部で3人の日本人パイロットを崇拝
It was around 1944
1944年頃のことでした
In fact, Taiwan was bombed by the US military again.
実際、台湾は再び米軍による空襲を受けました。
So Japan has the air force called the navy at that time
当時日本には海軍と呼ばれる空軍があった
The Navy's pilot flight team will take to the skies to meet
海軍のパイロット飛行チームが迎えに空へ飛び立つ
Of course they all hit a lot
もちろんどれも大ヒットですよ
Now the plane hits down at this place
今、飛行機がこの場所に着陸します
Three people on the plane died locally
飛行機に乗っていた3人が現地で死亡
The locals built a temple to worship them
地元の人々は彼らを崇拝するために寺院を建てました
This temple is very early, probably in the 50s to 60s
この寺院は非常に早く、約 50 ～ 60 年前に建てられました。
At the beginning, it should be called the Japanese Shogun’s Former Event Store.
最初は、日本将軍の旧イベントストアと呼ぶべきです。
I don't know how to come up with the name
名前のつけ方がわかりません
But at that time, I felt that talking about Japanese generals
しかし、当時私は日本の将軍について話すのは難しいと感じていました。
politically incorrect
政治不正確
So remove that day
だからその日を削除してください
That's why it is now called the General's Former Events Store.
そのため、現在は将軍の旧イベント ストアと呼ばれています。
it's normal
それは普通です
But now that temple is called General Ben’s Former Event Store
しかし現在、その寺院はベン将軍の旧イベントストアと呼ばれています
Japanese locals, I will explain it to you with white eyes
現地の日本人よ、白目で説明してください。
This is also around the end of the war
これも終戦直後のこと
A plane is going to Tainan Airport
飛行機が台南空港に向かっています
Then people in Tainan wait for that place to drop
そして台南の人々はその場所がなくなるのを待ちます
There are 14 people on it
14人いるよ
After death they worship them
死後、彼らは彼らを崇拝します
There are two portraits
肖像画が2枚あります
I have 14 portraits
ポートレートは14枚あります
I don't know how the name came from
名前の由来は分かりません
I think the same is what the chicken boy said
チキンボーイの言っていることも同じだと思う
name him yourself
自分で彼に名前を付ける
So this must have been a humble small temple
つまり、ここは質素な小さな寺院だったに違いありません
But later it gradually developed into a more decent
しかしその後、それは徐々によりまともなものに発展しました
Because there is such a supernatural legend
そんな超自然的な伝説があるから
Many of these temples are supernatural legends
これらの寺院の多くは超自然的な伝説です
And some are more and more powerful
そしていくつかはますます強力になっています
Many temples were later built bigger
多くの寺院は後にさらに大きく建てられました
Sunnah
スンナ
Sunnah for everyone go full name tag
スンナは全員にフルネームタグを付けます
If you make a fortune, come and renovate a temple for him
もしあなたが大金を儲けたら、彼のために神殿を改築しに来てください
Below we will have an example of this
以下にその例を示します
This temple is very remote
このお寺はとても辺鄙なところにあります
this is what the newspaper said
これは新聞が言ったことです
Said 311 after the earthquake
地震後に311って言った
Many people suddenly come here
突然ここに来る人も多い
hope he
希望他
are you a japanese god ? hurry up
あなたは日本の神様ですか? 急いでください
tie up you japanese safe
あなたを日本の安全な場所に縛り付けてください
This is similar
これも似ています
also a plane crash
飛行機事故も
Such supernatural legends
このような超自然的な伝説
In particular, this is a similar
特にこれに似ていると言われています。
that is
あれは
These
これらは
so that the Japanese soldiers here
ここにいる日本兵は
He can
彼はできる
Possess
所有する
Then you know that the soldiers and civilians in the single place have some strange phenomena
そうすると、兵士と民間人が同じ場所にいると、奇妙な現象が起きることがわかります。
for example
例えば
don't speak japanese at all
日本語を全く話さない
He started speaking Japanese one day
彼はある日日本語を話し始めた
Of course it's nonsense
もちろんナンセンスです
That short day everyone sounds like it's Japanese
あの短い日は誰もが日本人のように聞こえる
I can also sing Japanese songs
日本の歌も歌えます
just believe this is
これがそうだと信じてください
must be playing directly
直接プレイしている必要があります
doing something weird
何か変なことをしている
So just go when something like this usually happens
だから、こういうことがいつも起こるときに行ってください
I will definitely go to the big temple in Shandi
シャンディの大きな寺院には必ず行きます
like that even bigger god
もっと大きな神様みたいに
please tell me what the hell is going on
一体何が起こっているのか教えてください
Of course the gods will pass through the foundation
もちろん神々は基礎を通過します
or through hands-on
または実践を通じて
then tell you
それから教えてください
Hurry up and build a temple now
急いで神殿を建てなさい
Bye bye you'll be fine
バイバイ、大丈夫だよ
Many small temples worshiping Japanese gods
日本の神様を祀る小さな寺院がたくさんある
that's how it all came about
それがすべての始まりだった
this is not a soldier
これは兵士ではありません
This is a Japanese supervisor in the original Baibenmen factory
元祖白弁門工場の日本人監督です
it's called Q2
それはQ2と呼ばれます
because at that time
なぜならその時は
on their own sign
自分たちのサインの上に
There is a sign next to it
その横に看板があります
So they worshiped a
それで彼らは崇拝しました
used to work in this factory
以前この工場で働いていました
Factory director's Q yuan translation
工場長Q元訳
Actually it's Japanese Kanji
実は日本の漢字なんです
scrambled prefix an autumn Q
スクランブル プレフィックス オータム Q
There is a place called Hagi on Sankou Line
三江線に萩という場所があります
its idiom is famous
そのイディオムは有名です
I guess this Q should come from this Q
このQはこのQから来たものだと思います
So let's call it Q2
それでは第 2 四半期と呼びましょう
He said this Q2
彼はこの第2四半期にこう言いました
this Q2
この第2四半期
This long one is outside this place
この長いのはこの場所の外にあります
So many locals love it
たくさんの地元の人に愛されています
Later he died here
その後彼はここで亡くなった
later people will miss him
後で人々は彼を恋しく思うでしょう
It's the same situation as that of Yiai Palace.
イーアイパレスと同じ状況だ。
start worshiping him
彼を崇拝し始める
Gradually from a small temple to a chauvinistic temple
小さな寺院から徐々に排外的な寺院へ
But then I check
しかし、その後、私はチェックします
Wang Zhicheng, after we have the staff record of the Governor-General of Taiwan
王志誠の後は台湾総督の職員記録がある。
Our staff directory is a database
当社の社員名簿はデータベースです
All publicly owned from elementary school under the Governor of Taiwan
台湾総督以下の小学校からすべて公有
As long as you have your name, you can look it up
名前さえわかれば調べられるよ
let me check this guy
この男を調べさせてください
He wasn't dead in the time they say
彼らが言う時点では彼は死んでいなかった
It was he who left this place later
後でこの場所を去ったのは彼でした
Because I met somewhere else
どこかで会ったから
At least two years later he went to another place
少なくとも2年後、彼は別の場所に行った
Now of course I don't know
今はもちろん分かりません
Maybe go back to Japan
もしかしたら日本に帰るかもしれない
but they say
しかし彼らは言う
How often he said or wrote like this
彼はどのくらい頻繁にこのように言ったり書いたりしましたか
This is the man who died here to sense him
これは彼を感じるためにここで死んだ男です
this is not important
これは重要ではありません
it will have a japanese god bless people
日本の神が人々を祝福してくれるだろう
this is more important
これはもっと重要です
This is inside the fish farm
ここは養魚場の中にあります
There is also a fish farm temple
養殖寺院もあります
It's also like this
こんなのもあるよ
There must be supernatural phenomena
超常現象もあるはず
This is a small temple in the fish farm
ここは養魚場の中にある小さなお寺です
It is also a Yuwen Temple property
宇文寺の所有地でもあります
ok this
わかりました、これ
next this
次はこれ
Youyuwen Gong Temple has been upgraded
幽宇文宮がアップグレードされました
becomes a medium-sized temple
中規模の寺院となる
And it's very sunny now
そして今はとても晴れています
Now maybe all of Taiwan
おそらく台湾全体が
most famous in japan
最有名的日本
A temple worshiping Japanese gods
日本の神様を祀る神社
This temple is in Annan District
この寺院は安南区にあります
Annan District, Taiwan
台湾安南区
There is a big wild area called Haiwei
海尾と呼ばれる大きな野生地帯があります
Haiwei is an old place name
海尾は古い地名です
There are now a total of seven lis in this giant warm corridor at the end of the sea.
海の端にあるこの巨大な暖かい回廊には、現在合計 7 つのリスがあります。
you know how big its population is
人口がどれだけ多いか知っていますか
At the end of the sea there is a big temple called Chaohuan Palace
海の先には潮煥宮という大きな寺院があります。
The main god of Chaohuan Palace is Baosheng Dadi
潮環宮の主神は宝生大帝です。
that now
那現在
The original name of this temple is Zheng Nanpang
この寺院の元の名前は鄭南方です。
The locals commonly call it the Temple of the Flying Tiger General
地元の人々は一般にそれを飛虎将軍の寺院と呼んでいます
This temple was also
このお寺もそうでした
It turns out that this place is full of fish farms
この場所には養殖場がたくさんあることが判明しました
also the same
また同じです
And this, this is very specific
そしてこれ、これは非常に具体的です
not a legend
伝説ではない
That is to say, the time, the young age, the person, who is the person
つまり、時代、若さ、その人、その人は誰なのか
On this side, there's an air battle going on at this place
こちら側、この場所で空戦が起こっています
fierce air battle
激しい空戦
This valley, Maofeng, this flying man
この谷、猫峰、この空飛ぶ男
right around here
この辺で
was shot down and died here
ここで撃墜されて死亡した
was twenty-one when he died
彼が亡くなった時は21歳だった
that, after death
それは、死後に
At first, everyone thought it was unfair
最初は誰もが不公平だと思った
and later on it started to appear
そしてその後、それが現れ始めました
As I just said, someone rode a white horse in the middle of the night
先ほども言いましたが、真夜中に誰かが白馬に乗りました
Stories like this are everywhere
こういう話はどこにでもある
are all the same
どれも同じです
then started thinking about
それから考え始めました
Just ask Baosheng Dadi
Baosheng Dadiに聞いてください
I often ask Baosheng Dadi, and I say
私はよく宝生父迪に尋ねます、そして、私はこう言います。
that place
その場所
Of course not one
もちろん1つではありません
the flying man died there
空飛ぶ男はそこで死んだ
everyone immediately remember
誰もがすぐに覚えます
there is this
これはあります
so hurry to that place
だから急いでその場所へ
Build a small workshop and start
小さなワークショップを建てて始めましょう
Bye to the 1980s
拜到1980年代
because Café de Coral
カフェ・ド・コーラルなので
Everyone's Youth Card
みんなの青春カード
Someone must get rich from this
誰かがこれで金持ちになるに違いない
So this temple was refurbished to be very beautiful
それでこの寺院はとても美しく改装されました
Then Caowan Palace put it
それからカオワンパレスはそれを置きました
Accepting it is equivalent to Jiaotou Temple
それを受け入れることは焦頭寺と同等です
It is a small settlement in this atmosphere
この雰囲気の小さな集落です
inside a temple
寺院の中
Caowan Palace unified to manage
草湾宮の一元管理
That
それか
because this
なぜならこれは
The story is too specific
話が具体的すぎる
That's because no one knows
それは誰も知らないから
Because when the pilot fell
パイロットが墜落したときだから
His shoes have his name on them
彼の靴には彼の名前が付いています
So it's easy to find out
だから調べるのは簡単だよ
his coming
彼が来る
where is he from
彼はどこから来ましたか
He is a japanese paranoid nurse
彼は日本の偏執的な看護師です
from a soldier
兵士から
a pilot
一個飛行員
then behind me
それから私の後ろに
I'll charge you a little more later
後ほど少し追加料金をいただきます
things to go back to visit relatives
親戚に会いに帰るもの
You can take a look first
まずは見てみてもいいよ
Just now this is the appearance of the temple
先ほどのお寺の様子です
This whole look is like this
全体の見た目はこんな感じ
what's in there
そこには何がありますか
his door
彼のドア
General Flying Tiger
フライングタイガー将軍
hang this all year
これを一年中吊るしておいてください
welcome
いらっしゃいませ
Ladies and gentlemen, Japan
各位日本
Friends who rent a seat from Japan come here to pay homage
日本から席を借りた友人たちが敬意を表するためにここに来ます
use Japanese
日本語を使う
Because there are too many visitors from Japan
日本からの観光客が多すぎるので
On average I asked about 600 Japanese people a year recently
私は最近、年間平均約600人の日本人に質問しました。
come here
ここに来て
Whether tourists or believers come, anyway, they will come here to visit or pay homage.
観光客が来るにしろ、信者が来るにしろ、とにかく参拝や参拝に来ます。
About 600 or so in recent years
近年では約600件程度
So he will be
それで彼はそうするだろう
This is his main hall
ここが彼の本堂です
His home is small here
ここの彼の家は小さいです
there is one
ここに一つ
Republic of China flag Japan flag
中華民国の旗 日本の国旗
Then
それから
this is his picture
これは彼の写真です
why this photo
なぜこの写真があるのですか
because later
後でだから
When you start building this temple, you will know my name when you know my name.
あなたがこの神殿を建て始めるとき、私の名前を知ったとき、あなたは私の名前を知るでしょう。
Even this clue to check
この確認の手がかりさえも
Find his information in Japan
日本で彼の情報を探す
Their
彼らの
as if his sister was still there
まるで彼の妹がまだそこにいるかのように
decades ago
数十年前
So go to the photo provided
それで、提供された写真に行きます
So there is this in this temple
このお寺にはこんなものがあるのですね
this japanese town
この日本の街
This photo of Flying Tiger General
フライング タイガー ジェネラルのこの写真
Whistle
ホイッスル
Then
それから
because this
なぜならこれは
The deity of this temple is very specific
この神社の神様はとても個性的です
so
それで
easy to advertise
宣伝しやすい
make luggage
做行箱
So more and more Japanese will come
そうすると日本人もどんどん来ますよ
By 2015
2015年までに
This frequent Japanese
この頻繁な日本人は
they even
彼らさえも
They have an organization like the Continuous Workers' Association
継続労働者協会のような組織がある
There are several chapters in Japan
日本にはいくつかの支部がある
it's all about this
それはすべてこれについてです
This is related to the Temple of the Flying Tiger General
これは飛虎将軍の神殿に関連しています。
they are
彼らです
in osaka
在大阪
exist
存在
There are still several in Kansai and Kanto
関西や関東にもまだいくつかあります
this representative office
この駐在員事務所
then usually come
それなら普通に来るよ
sometimes contact each other
時々連絡し合う
They donated together
彼らは一緒に寄付しました
they later found out that
彼らは後でそれを知りました
Neither of the classrooms of this restored general
この復元された将軍の教室はどちらもありませんでした
every March 15
毎年3月15日
Avenue Palace is Baosheng Land
アベニューパレスは宝生ランドです
when the christmas parade goes around
クリスマスパレードが回るとき
Our recovery generals don't have classrooms to do
私たちの回復将軍にはやるべき教室がありません
I have to borrow someone else's classroom
他の人の教室を借りなければなりません
Squeeze in and teach with others
参加して他の人と一緒に教える
So they decided to donate
そこで彼らは寄付をすることにしました
Just do a little Japanese-style Shintoism
ちょっとだけ日本式神道をやってみよう
So in 2015
それで2015年に
Consecration is a Taiwanese concept
奉献は台湾の概念です
There is no such thing as consecration in Japan
日本には奉献などというものはない
But since the owner of the entry
しかし、エントリの所有者以来、
so after delivery
それで納品後
Baosheng Land
保生大地
should say
言うべきだ
Duke Cao's mage performed a consecration ceremony for him
曹公の魔術師は彼のために聖別の儀式を行った
then Japan
然後日本
also invited one
も1人招待されました
Priest of the shrine
神社的神官
Come do a ceremony
儀式をしに来てください
this chinese style
この中国風
Japanese style is done
和風が完成しました
Then I also participated in Taoism that year
そしてその年、私も道教に参加しました
this was two years ago
これは2年前のことです
well , a funny thing happened last year
さて、去年面白いことが起こりました
Because many Japanese people come
日本人もたくさん来るので
So this temple civilization is because there were several Japanese writers later
つまり、この寺院文明は、後に何人かの日本人作家がいたからである
Cleverly introduce this temple and write the story of this person
このお寺を上手に紹介し、この人の物語を綴る
This Japanese man has become a god here
この日本人男性はここで神になった
Worshiped like this by Taiwanese
台湾人にはこう崇拝される
So more Japanese will come to see
もっと多くの日本人が見に来ますように
Well, there was a Japanese female writer last spring
さて、昨年の春に日本の女性作家がいました
Suddenly came to the Temple of General Flying Tiger
突然フライングタイガー将軍の神殿にやって来た
He told the people in the temple
彼は神殿の人々にこう言いました。
This Flying Tiger General holds a dream
フライングタイガー将軍には夢がある
Tell me he wants to go back to the bible
彼が聖書に戻りたいと言ってください
He wants to go back to Japan to have a look
彼は日本に戻って様子を見たいと思っています
He's already, you see 1944
彼はすでに 1944 年にいます
by 2016
2016年までに
It's been a few years since I went back
戻ってきてから数年が経ちました
so he wants to go back and have a look
それで彼は戻って見てみたいと思っています
Well, if you want to go back, of course you have to form a group
まあ、戻りたければ、もちろんグループを作らなければなりません
which god is going out
どの神が出て行くのか
that will cost a lot of money
それには多額の費用がかかるでしょう
So the chairperson of Prince Cao is Wu Jingci
つまり、曹操王子の議長は呉京慈です。
He thinks it's more prudent
彼はそれがより賢明だと考えている
so he said
それで彼は言いました
because of what you said
あなたが言ったことのせいで
I'm already in the temple baby
もうお寺にいるよ、ベイビー
get three holy splendor
得三個聖輝
It's true that I'm not lying
嘘じゃないのは本当だよ
The head committee member of that temple said it was insincere
その寺院の委員長は、それは不誠実であると述べた
only if i come
私が来たらだけ
so he said i come baby
だから彼は私が来るって言った、ベイビー
see if it's true
それが本当かどうか見てください
he started really started baby
彼は本当に始めました、ベイビー
Eight times in a row are holy brilliance
8回連続は聖なる輝き
this is weird
これは奇妙だ
This should not exist in terms of mathematical memory.
これは数学的記憶の観点からは存在しないはずです。
but there is
しかし〜がある
Then after getting eight holy radiances
そして8つの聖なる輝きを手に入れた後
The chairman said
会長は言いました
Ringo baby
リンゴベイビー
He said what if the ninth is Shenghui again?
彼は、9番目がまたシェンフイだったらどうなるだろうと言いました。
Nine is the emperor's honor
9は皇帝の名誉です
He said that our Shenghui is lonely and tall
彼は、私たちの盛輝は孤独で背が高いと言いました
can't get to this
これにはたどり着けない
us
私たち
Netizens are not enough
ネチズンだけでは十分ではない
how can i use wine
ワインをどうやって使えばいいのか
so
それで
For fear of nine hymns in a row
９回連続の賛美歌が怖いから
He stopped at eight
彼は8時に止まった
This is the chairman
こちらが会長です
I'm going to visit him
彼を訪ねるつもりです
He himself said he wouldn't lie
本人も嘘はつかないって言ってた
i know i have known him for many years
私は彼を何年も知っていることを知っています
So they really go back in September
それで彼らは本当に9月に戻ります
26 people formed a group to go back
26人がグループに戻った
Go back to visit relatives with the idol
アイドルと一緒に親戚に会いに戻る
to visit his hometown
彼の故郷を訪れる
Because he, the Flying Tiger General
だって彼はフライングタイガー将軍だから
there are some relatives
親戚が何人かいます
so to his hometown
それで彼の故郷へ
Water nurses go around the border
水の看護師が国境を巡る
didn't hear the rain
雨の音は聞こえなかった
i watched that video
私はそのビデオを見ました
wow, that's a lot of people
うわー、人が多いですね
at home
自宅で
Still borrowing the religion of the single place
たった一つの場所の宗教を借り続けている
Japanese religion
日本の宗教
Detour as a water nurse
水の看護師としての回り道
then go to his two schools
それから彼の2つの学校に行きます
He went to two primary schools and went back to visit
彼は2つの小学校に行き、また遊びに行きました
school closed
学校閉鎖
First open the door over there to welcome the seniors
まずはドアを向こうに誘導して先輩たちをお迎えします
The best part is the latter
一番良いのは後者です
Then until September 24th
その後9月24日まで
they are going to tokyo
彼らは東京に行く予定です
why go to tokyo
なぜ東京に行くのか
Because actually going through Tokyo
実際に東京を通過しているので、
Mingoya
ミンゴヤ
because of this
このため
when you sit down say
座ったら言う
When the general of Huifu left with me
恵府の将軍が私と一緒に去ったとき
in my dream
私の夢の中で
Mount Fuji keeps appearing
富士山が現れ続ける
Maybe he wants to see Mount Fuji
たぶん彼は富士山を見たいのでしょう
so
それで
In order to let the general of the Huifu
恵府の将軍にさせるために
this wish
この願い
so they start with
それで彼らは始まります
Because Cicheng County is in the northeast of Tokyo
慈城県は東京の北東にあるので、
To go to the mainland through the northeast
東北を通って本土へ行くには
Go to Mingoya to see Mount Fuji
富士山を見に民小屋へ行く
So that day is to
それでその日は
going to see mount fuji
富士山を見に行く
Mito
水戸
take a ride
乗ります
when going to tokyo
東京に行くとき
that's the line
それがラインです
What about the express car of this RR?
このRRの特急車はどうでしょうか？
It's just that it doesn't stop at every station.
ただ、各駅に止まらないんです。
Many stations are non-stop
多くの駅はノンストップです
to this
これに
The second rendering of the map city
地図都市の 2 番目のレンダリング
There is a station called Arakawa Oki Station
荒川沖駅という駅があります。
should pass
通過する必要があります
is non-stop
ノンストップです
This station is non-stop
この駅はノンストップです
As a result, it stopped suddenly before passing the station.
その結果、駅を通過する手前で急停止した。
on emergency braking
急ブレーキをかけると
like emergency braking
緊急ブレーキのような
just stopped suddenly
突然止まっただけ
That
それか
where they walked together
彼らが一緒に歩いた場所
There is a president of a Japanese mountain club
有一個日本山社的一個社長
It's called Dachuan Yanqi Line
大川延斉線といいます。
Is to follow them all the way to receive them
受け取るためにずっと追いかけることです
just go with them
ただ彼らと一緒に行きましょう
He's sitting right across from that god's box
彼は神の箱の真向かいに座っている
he finds it strange
彼はそれが奇妙だと思う
why don't you stop at this stop
この停留所に止まってみませんか
and not stop at the station
そして駅には止まらない
stop outside
外で止まる
So he went to ask the train conductor
そこで彼は車掌に聞きに行きました
you do not know
あなたは知らない
The car stopped suddenly
車が突然止まった
The car later had Guangdong
車には後に広東省があった
Because I'm going to tell the police why I stopped
警察に止めた理由を言うから
because there shouldn't be parking
駐車場が無いはずだから
He said because there is a level crossing ahead
この先に踏切があるからと彼は言った
there seems to be something
何かがあるようです
let's pause
一時停止しましょう
But it's not the reason
でもそれが理由ではない
just don't know why stop
なぜ止めるのか分からない
After the big rumorer went to ask
大物噂話者が聞きに行った後
When he came back it suddenly occurred to him to say
戻ってきたとき、彼は突然こう言いました。
this place
この場所
parking place
停車的地方
It was the mountain spectrum back then
それは当時の山岳スペクトルでした
Brave the wind, the birthday star's Canyon Starfish Air Force
風に勇敢に、誕生日スターのキャニオン・スターフィッシュ空軍
next to
の隣に
As far as he started to go
彼が歩き始めたところまでは
Before flying, birthday boy
飛ぶ前に、誕生日の男の子
The first base is here
最初の拠点はここです
I didn’t come to Taiwan until after the birthday party over there
向こうでの誕生日パーティーの後、台湾に来ました
near the parking lot
駐車場の近く
so this one
それでこれ
President of Big Rumors
ビッグ・ルーマー社の社長
This is according to Wu Jingci's description
これは呉静慈氏の説明によると、
Came back and suddenly thought of this
帰ってきて、ふとこんなことを思い出した
this point he said
この点について彼は言った
here is the canyon
ここが峡谷です
That's the one
それだ
That flight base
あの飛行基地
treatment
処理
So Lie Shi why is he listening here because
それで、Lie Shiはなぜここで聞いているのですか？
General Flying Tiger wants to take a look and listen here
フライング タイガー将軍はここを見て聞いてみたいと考えています
He said he didn't believe in any gods
彼は神を信じていないと言いました
he suddenly
他突然
just stay
ただ滞在してください
Facing the voice of the Flying Tiger General, start
飛虎将軍の声に向かってスタート
keep playing keep playing
遊び続けて遊び続ける
This is not nonsense because this one
これはナンセンスではありません、なぜならこれは
big sailor president
大船員 社長
Posted this on his facebook that day
その日、自身のフェイスブックにこう投稿した
jump on the net
ネットに飛び乗る
He told the story
彼はその話をしました
Mark the map, this is General Flying Tiger
地図にマークを付けてください、これはフライング タイガー将軍です
sit in this car
この車に座ってください
this right
これは正しい
For those of Prince Cao, this is called a supernatural deed.
曹操皇子にとって、これは神業と呼ばれるものです。
This is hard to explain, I don't know why
これは説明が難しいので、理由がわかりません
It may be accidental, the car just broke down
偶然かも知れません、車が故障しただけです
but just by chance
でもたまたま
For happiness, that is not important
幸せにとって、それは重要ではありません
this is supernatural
これは超自然的です
not important to outsiders
部外者にとっては重要ではない
For them, they will be more difficult to get
彼らにとっては、入手がさらに困難になるだろう
to market this temple
この寺院を売り出すために
to market this god
この神を売り出すために
this is a story
これは物語です
But it's a true story
でもそれは本当の話です
nice story we people say
私たちが言う素敵な話
similar to this
これに似たもの
General Flying Tiger , the pilot shot it down
パイロットによって撃墜されたフライング タイガー将軍
In fact, Pingtung also has a
実は屏東にも、
Otherwise he is not as famous as General Flying Tiger
そうでなければ彼はフライングタイガー将軍ほど有名ではない
He is a shikigami in the temple
彼はお寺の式神です
So a plane is provided
それで上に飛行機があります
Just say Mita, what?
ミタって言って、何？
But it's impossible not to know his name
でも彼の名前を知らないわけがない
Suddenly there is a big temple
突然大きなお寺が現れました
In fact, you have Yingong Temple
実は、インゴン寺院があります。
Don't think it must be small
小さいはずだと思わないでください
There is a big staff temple
大きなスタッフ寺院があります
This staff temple
このスタッフ寺院
It was built very large from the beginning
最初からとても大きく建てられました
Because this is the Wurengong Temple built by the Taiwan Municipal Government
なぜなら、ここは台湾市政府が建てた武人宮廟だからです。
The reason why the temple of Wurengong was built is because
武人功寺が建てられた理由は次のとおりです。
in 1964
1964年に
This modern Zhongshan Junior High School
この近代的な中山中学校
It wants a sports factory to expand
スポーツファクトリーの拡大が必要
Then, because the school was located before, it became a kind of kind outside the gate.
そうすると、前に学校があったので、門外のような形になりました。
It's chaos
混沌だ
so
それで
playground to be expanded
拡張される遊び場
The human bones of more than a thousand giants were actually dug up
千体以上の巨人の人骨が実際に発掘された
that's one of the few
それは数少ないうちの一つです
I know it's Japanese
それが日本語であることは知っています
Because the packaging is different
パッケージが違うので
it's late
遅いです
then there is
それからあります
which since it is installed in that
その中にロードされているので、
Tight knife
緊刀昂
inside that duck
あのアヒルの中には
Another one with a name
もう一つは名前付き
call auspicious words
縁起の良い言葉を呼ぶ
it's the name i've always known
それは私がいつも知っている名前です
Then he said that because of this human bone
すると彼は、この人骨のせいでこう言いました。
this bone is too much
この骨は多すぎる
Find a place to put it after digging it out
掘り出したら置き場所を探す
After the bones appeared, all kinds of dreams began to appear. Everyone began to dream.
骨が現れてからは、あらゆる種類の夢が現れ始め、誰もが夢を見るようになりました。
That is to say, there is a general named Xie Yongchang in Zheng Chenggong's time
つまり、鄭成功の時代に謝永昌という将軍がいるのです。
That's why it's called Marshal Xiefu
それが謝夫元帥と呼ばれる理由です
Zheng Chenggong's department will not have a Xie Yongchang
鄭成功氏の部門には謝永昌氏はいない
Because we have to actually check
実際に確認する必要があるので、
I guess most of them are also created
それらのほとんども作成されたものだと思います
not necessarily real
必ずしも本物ではない
There is another called General Zhao Sheng
趙勝将軍と呼ばれるもう一人がいます
next to him
彼の隣に
this is a japanese
これは日本人です
So 332 represents
したがって、332 は次のことを表します。
built this staff temple
この杖廟を建てました
Judge the three of them
三人を裁いてください
So he still uses the Japanese pretense
だから彼はまだ日本のふりをしている
dress up
着飾る
just started 1960s
剛開始1960年代
To build this temple is the same as the political correctness problem just mentioned.
この寺院を建てるというのは、先ほどのポリティカル・コレクトネスの問題と同じです。
a japanese god
日本の神様
so name him
それで彼に名前を付けます
at the begining of
の初めに
that's all
それで全部です
Jiyuan Elementary School teaches that it is called Xie Jiyuan
済園小学校は謝済園と呼ばれています。
So he is Xie Yongchang's deployment
つまり、彼は謝永昌の配備です
So let's surname Xie together
だから一緒に謝の姓を名乗ろう
So it's called Xie Jiyuan
だからシェ・ジーユアンといいます
but you pay attention
でもあなたは注意します
this temple
この寺院
his
他的
two pillars
2本の柱
is to use pole and element
極と要素を使用することです
beginning
始まり
Jiyuan Xiaojiao
済源小角
So from the very beginning, I attached great importance to this Japanese
ですから、私は最初からこの日本語を非常に重視していました。
this pants bone
このパンツの骨
What about more than a thousand bones?
千以上の骨はどうなるのでしょうか？
Still behind this temple
まだこの寺院の裏側にあります
sue a big priest
大司祭を訴える
I put it over there
あそこに置きました
because I went to see
見に行ったので
i did it last time
前回もやりました
when doing business
ビジネスをするとき
As long as someone comes to look at that temple, people will come to ask
その寺院を見に来る人がいる限り、人々は尋ねに来るでしょう
What's your business
あなたのビジネスは何ですか
I said no, I just came and took a look
私はノーと言いました、ちょっと見に来ただけです
Are you from the National Social Security Bureau?
国家社会保障局の方ですか？
Because their temple is built on the land of the state-owned election bureau
彼らの寺院は国営選挙局の敷地内に建てられているため、
state-owned electoral bureau
国営選挙局
now tell them
今彼らに伝えてください
before
前
So the party-state part is not necessarily bad
つまり政党と国家の部分は必ずしも悪いわけではない
It used to be a part of the party and government
かつては党や政府の一部だった
so
それで
Tainan City Government
台南市政府
Just built a temple as big as Yungong Temple
雲公寺と同じくらい大きな寺院を建てたところです
built on the land of the state-owned electoral bureau
国営選挙局の敷地に建てられた
Does the National Election Bureau have any comments?
中央選挙管理局から何かコメントはありますか。
but now
でも今
you are you and i am me
あなたはあなたで、私は私です
The temples in the central area are clearly divided
中央エリアの寺院は明確に分かれています
So the National Election Bureau
そこで国選局は、
come to the city hall
市役所に来てください
The city government said that I am not using that land either.
市役所もその土地は使っていないと言いました。
It's that temple, you go to that temple to ask for money
それはその寺院です、あなたはお金を求めるためにその寺院に行きます
That temple now has its own management committee
その寺院は現在、独自の管理委員会を持っています
So the chairman of the management committee has a headache
だから経営委員長は頭が痛いんだよ
He said the National Election Bureau said you were going to give us
彼は、全国選挙管理局があなたが私たちに与えるつもりだと言ったと言いました
Tens of thousands of rent
家賃数万
we have no money
私たちにはお金がありません
There will be no fire in this temple
この寺院には火はありません
so he looked
それで彼は見た
Some people think about it first
最初に考える人もいる
The National Election Bureau wants to see
国政選挙管理局が知りたいこと
to take back their temple property
神殿の財産を取り戻すために
This is not well run
これはうまく運営されていません
Okay, Kaohsiung and Pingtung also have a famous Japanese
そう、高雄や屏東にも有名な日本人がいます。
Worshiping the Japanese gods
日本の神々を崇拝する
This Fengshan now has a very beautiful temple called Baoantang
この鳳山には現在、宝安堂と呼ばれる非常に美しい寺院があります。
You will see those Hongmaogang security halls
ホンマオガン保安ホールが見えます
Hongmao Port is a small port in Kaohsiung
紅茂港は高雄の小さな港です。
A former fishing village by the sea
かつての海沿いの漁村
Later, the port of Kaohsiung was expanded
その後、高雄港が拡張されました
There must be the entire thousand villages of Hongmaogang
紅毛港の千の村は全部あるに違いない
Some people led to Fengshan
鳳山に導かれた人もいる
Just in this place to restore the little temple where they used to be
ちょうどこの場所に、彼らがかつてあった小さな寺院を復元するために
here to renovate
ここで改装します
Don't call it renovation, rebuild it into a big temple
改修と言うな、大きな寺院に建て替えろ
The same name is Hongmaogang Security Hall
同じ名前は紅毛港保衛館です
Hongmaogang Security Hall
ホンマオガン保安ホール
thanks
ありがとう
It is more standard with Yin Gong Temple
銀宮寺の方が標準的です
because they carry three bones
骨が3本あるから
first
第一次
Let's go out to Hong Kong zero one zero
香港ゼロワンへ出かけよう
Japan picked up an ancient pulse in ten generations
日本は10世代かけて古代の鼓動を拾い上げた
so come back
だから戻ってきて
When I came back, I confessed that I was called the Marshal of the Central Government.
戻ってきたとき、私は中央政府の元帥と呼ばれていたことを告白しました。
This second time is also suitable for the pre-war
この二回目も戦前に相応しい
Kokufu Chitose
甲府・千歳
Pick up a Skull Valley after the battle
戦闘後にスカルバレーを拾う
I don't know why it's called Marshal of the Haifu
なぜハイフの元帥と呼ばれるのか分かりません
It is now the residence of the security group.
現在は治安部隊の住居となっている。
I didn't know who he was
彼が誰なのか知りませんでした
Anyway, because the fish catcher picked up this thing
とにかく、フィッシュキャッチャーがこれを拾ったので、
I feel more peaceful when I go back.
戻ってくると、より穏やかな気持ちになります。
I hope there will be no accidents to defend the fish goods
魚介類を守るために事故が無いことを祈ります
make a fortune
大金を稼ぐ
and then later
そしてその後
He actually said he picked it up for the last time
実は彼は最後にそれを手に取ったと言っていた
Supreme Commander of Kaifu in Cranial Valley
頭蓋谷的海府大元帥
Said that at the same time the captain of the Japanese warship
同時に日本の軍艦の艦長はこう言った。
Of course it was a dream or through the machine barrel
もちろん夢だったり機銃越しだったり
and also said
そしてまた言った
Adding it to Okinawa makes Ryukyu
沖縄に加えると琉球になる
and it's clear
そしてそれは明らかです
I am the head of the No. 38 economy
私は No.38 エコノミーのビルダーです
So "Red Maoya" in 1990 really
1990年の「レッドマオヤ」は本当に
Expanded
拡張された
Okinawa has one
沖縄にもあるよ
memorial pile reads
記念碑の読み物
There is a record that building 38 was integrated
38号館が統合された記録あり
very scattered
非常に散らばっている
But what is Building No. 38?
しかし、38号館とは何でしょうか？
that's not an economy
それは経済ではありません
Zhengyang Special Agent Field
鄭陽特別捜査官フィールド
Japan had suicide planes late in the war
日本は戦争末期に特攻機を持っていた
There are also suicide buildings
自殺ビルもある
very small
非常に少ない
One boat makes two people
１つのボートで２人になります
just to attack
ただ攻撃するためだけに
The economy of the US military and the Allies
米軍と連合国の経済
So it's actually a very small boat
実はとても小さな船なんです
but now
でも今
how can our god make such a small boat
私たちの神はどうやってあんな小さな船を作ることができるのでしょうか
So let's expand it
それでは拡張してみましょう
it is a warship
それは軍艦です
Warship 38
軍艦38
So they have another 9 foot long
つまり、彼らはさらに9フィートの長さを持っています
How much is 9 feet? 270 cm
9 フィートはいくらですか? 270 cm
Of course not too big
もちろん大きすぎない
But there must be officers and soldiers
でも将校も兵士もいるはずだ
There were only 36
36個しかなかった
I don't think it's enough
十分ではないと思います
72 now
現在72
Actually that
実はそれ
There are only two people on the Zhenyang Ship
鎮陽船には二人しか乗っていない
Then three days a month the horn will be blown
それから月に3日はクラクションが鳴らされます
It's better to play Japanese songs
日本の曲をやったほうがいいよ
If you don't believe it, grow a 3.69
信じられないなら、3.69 を育ててください
I'm going to experience it too
私も体験してみます
Then 2003, 2001, 2005
その後、2003年、2001年、2005年
They have formed three groups
彼らは3つのグループを結成しました
Go to Jinxiang Shrine in Tokyo
東京の金祥神社へ行く
Because their main god is Japanese
彼らの主神は日本人だから
So Lin Yunchuan has a ranking in the Jin Kingdom God Society
つまり、リン・ユンチュアンは晋王国神協会のランクにあります
So go there Jinxiang
だからそこに行きなさい ジンシャン
In 2005, this time it was on Facebook
2005年、今度はFacebook上でした
I also saw their ad
彼らの広告も見ました
ok , this is the security team
OK、こちらはセキュリティチームです
It has just been built, and it has only been built in the past two years
建てられたばかりで、ここ 2 年以内に建てられたばかりです
According to their own words, this is your man Gallius
彼ら自身の言葉によると、これはあなたの男ガリウスです
I don't know, I don't know who designed this anyway
分からない、とにかく誰がこれをデザインしたのか分からない
In short, it is not purely Taiwanese or Chinese-style architecture
つまり、純粋な台湾式や中国式の建築ではないのです。
The two dragon pillars at the front
正面の二本の龍柱
It was donated by the Japan-Taiwan Qingshan Yongxing and the Qingshan Yongxing Cultural Group, with words engraved on it
日台の青山永興と青山永興文化団体から寄贈され、文字が刻まれている。
Temples like this will have Japanese donations
このような寺院には日本人の寄付が必要です
Donate not much, but there will be
寄付は多くありませんが、寄付は行われます
The temple is also very interesting
お寺もなかなか面白いですよ
This is their Zhenyang Sword
これが彼らの鎮陽剣です
Zhenyang Special Factory, now called No. 38
鎮陽特別工場、現在は第38工場と呼ばれています
This is Taiwanese very creative
これはとてもクリエイティブな台湾人です
Japanese is absolutely not written by me
日本語は絶対に私が書いたものではありません
but it was written by me
でもそれは私が書いたものです
Nichang Gungang
ニチャングンガン
Japanese warship
日本軍艦
There are left and right writing here
ここには左右の書き込みがあります
There is a Japanese-style Shinto religion in the temple
寺院には日本風の神道があります
The date changes every day
日付は毎日変わります
It is to allow you to take photos and practice here when you come to visit or pay homage.
参拝や参拝の際にここで写真撮影や練習ができるようにするためです
know what day you came
何日に来たか知っていますか
so this has the date on it
これには日付が入っています
I took the photo on March 14, 2016
2016年3月14日に撮影しました
this temple is now
この寺院は今
i'm red
私は赤いです
Because the back cover of the temple is very beautiful this time
今回は神殿の裏表紙がとても綺麗なので
Usually Japanese come
普通に日本人が来るんだよ
There are several temples in the south that you will go to
南部にはいくつかの寺院がありますので、行ってみましょう
So after you visit General Temple, you will go to Baoan Hall
将軍寺を訪れた後、宝安殿に行きます。
After visiting the Baoantang, go to Pingtung
宝安堂を訪れた後は屏東へ。
The Southeast Palace introduced below
以下で紹介する東南宮殿
Let's introduce a small temple first
まずは小さなお寺をご紹介します
There are Japanese gods in the village
村には日本の神様がいる
in Donggang
東港で
This Gonghe New Village is Dapeng Bay
この公河新村は大鵬湾です
Next to it is the Military Military Village of the Air Force's system
その隣には空軍の軍事村があります
This must be an affair project
これは不倫プロジェクトに違いない
He chose a Taiwanese wife
彼は台湾人の妻を選んだ
This Taiwanese wife is trustworthy
この台湾人妻は信頼できる
So I opened a Buddhist temple at home
それで自宅に仏教寺院を開きました
opened the temple
寺院を開いた
you don't mind
気にしないでください
This is
これは
The name of the dependent village
従属村の名前
then this
それからこれ
An old house left from the Japanese era
日本統治時代から残る古民家
There are many air-raid shelters in the late battle village
後期戦闘村には防空壕が多数ある
so this house
それでこの家
There's a bomb shelter next to it
隣に防空壕がある
He's right here in the bomb shelter
彼はここ防空壕の中にいます
This is the bomb shelter
ここが防空壕です
on this mountain
この山の上で
divided now
今分割されました
Drawn a Japanese flag
日本の国旗を描きました
Then he is here
それから彼はここにいます
bomb shelter this place
防空壕 ここ
this is the bomb shelter
ここは防空壕です
everyone look at this
みんなこれを見て
on this mountain
この山の上で
divided now
今分割されました
Drawn a Japanese flag
日本の国旗を描きました
so he's here
だから彼はここにいるよ
bomb shelter this place
防空壕 ここ
this is the bomb shelter
ここは防空壕です
everyone look at this
みんなこれを見て
Then gave the Japanese people a name
そして日本人に名前を付けました
I don't know how to read this
これの読み方がわかりません
No one goes to worship, anyway, it is his private Buddhist hall
誰も参拝に行かない、とにかく自分専用の仏堂だ
In addition, Donggang also has a place called Linsheng Church.
また、東港には林生堂という場所もあります。
He turned out to be the Hall of Fire
彼は火の殿堂であることが判明した
Now a small building has been built in the place of Huozhan Hall.
現在、火善堂の場所には小さな建物が建てられています。
The same is the Yungong Temple
雲公寺も同じです
same worship these
これらを同じように崇拝します
Japan in the Bashi Strait in the later stages of the war
戦争末期のバシー海峡の日本
Whether it's a cargo ship or a warship
貨物船でも軍艦でも
Many were bombed by the U.S. military
多くは米軍による爆撃を受けた
So in fact, there are a lot of Japanese in Bashi Strait, Warbashi Strait
実際、バシー海峡、ワルバシ海峡にはたくさんの日本人がいます。
So Taiwan is close to the place in Russia Ambi
つまり、台湾はロシアのアンビの場所に近いのです
There is a Buddhist temple built by the Japanese
日本人が建てた仏教寺院がある
Worship these, he will come here every year to worship these undead
これらを崇拝しなさい、彼はこれらのアンデッドを崇拝するために毎年ここに来ます
Like this is the fire battlefield that built him in Donggang
これが東港に彼を築いた火の戦場のようです
When he comes to the meeting every year, he will make model gold coupons, so that the dead of the Japanese army can use them
彼は毎年この会合に来ると、日本軍の戦没者が使えるようにモデルの金券を作るつもりだ。
Then these characters must have been mentioned by Keith
そしてこれらの文字はキースによって言われたに違いありません
Just take a few Japanese names
日本人の名前をいくつか挙げてみましょう
sorry
ごめん
Well, this Dongyang Palace is a very special
さて、この東陽宮は非常に特別です
It still has Yinggong Temple, but it is very large
英公寺はまだありますが、非常に大きいです
This ginseng village of this house
この家のこの高麗人参の里
There is a bomb shelter in this place
こんなところに防空壕があるんだ
It is generally called a bat cave, the house cave is very large, and there are many bats in it
一般的にコウモリの洞窟と呼ばれており、家の洞窟は非常に広く、その中にはコウモリがたくさんいます
And at his gate, there is a man's temple, called General Tanaka's Mansion
そして彼の門には、田中将軍の邸宅と呼ばれる男の寺院があります
Why is it called General Tanaka's Mansion?
なぜ田中将軍の邸宅と呼ばれているのですか？
Because I heard that at the end of the war
終戦の時に聞いたから
some japanese died
日本人が何人か亡くなった
come stand near here
ここの近くに立ってください
to worship these
これらを崇拝するために
Because the Japanese represent
日本人が代表するから
So I took a Japanese name
それで私は日本名を付けました
That's why it's called Shogun Tanaka
だから将軍タナカと呼ばれる
This princess of Duke Dongrong
このドンロン公爵の王女は
Dong Rong Gong is a private temple
Dong Rong Gong は私的な寺院です
The princess named Shi
シーという名の王女
He said she was in the 1980s
彼女は1980年代だったと言った
about eight years
約8年
She said she suddenly regained her spirit one day
彼女はある日突然霊力を取り戻したと言います
make her very uncomfortable
彼女をとても不快にさせる
She kept resisting but couldn't resist
彼女は抵抗し続けたが、抵抗できなかった
so and because dear
だから、そして愛する人だから
I have experienced it myself
私自身も経験しました
this deity japanese deity
この神 日本の神
Saying is an instruction
言うことは指示です
Many things come true
たくさんのことが叶う
so she started to believe
それで彼女は信じ始めた
And then she's talking in her house, priest
そして彼女は家で話しています、司祭
all these gods
これらすべての神々
she wants to save the world
彼女は世界を救いたいと思っています
So they usually say go to the altar
それで彼らはいつも祭壇に行きなさいと言います
called come out
出て来いと呼ばれた
their word is sacrifice
彼らの言葉は犠牲です
Their pattern is very high
彼らのパターンは非常に高いです
the wonderful thing is
素晴らしいことは
he later
彼は後で
After the altar is opened for sacrifice, there will be recovery
祭壇が犠牲のために開かれた後、回復が起こります
Because believers will give red envelopes
信者が赤い封筒をくれるから
Let's ask Lin Yan
リン・ヤンに聞いてみましょう
He will pack a big red envelope
彼は大きな赤い封筒を詰めるでしょう
So the economic situation started to improve
それで経済状況は改善し始めた
After transformation, he started to build a temple
変身後、彼は神殿を建て始めた
East Dragon Palace
東龍宮
At the beginning, his main god was Tanaka Goto
当初の主神は田中後藤でした。
Why is the main god called Tanaka Goto?
なぜ主神は田中後藤と呼ばれるのでしょうか？
He said it was the god
彼はそれが神だと言いました
tell me his name
彼の名前を教えてください
Then there are a few people who accompany me
それから私に同行する人が数人います
One is Minamimaki Nishida
一個是南牧西田
Nanmoku Nishida is very famous
南牧西田很有名
Former Governor of Taiwan
元台湾総督
actually
実際
It is not uncommon for Nanmu Xitian to also worship at the temple
南武西天もこの寺院で礼拝することは珍しいことではありません。
because when it was accepted in 1895
なぜならそれが1895年に受け入れられたとき
Nanmu Xitian led the Second Army
南武西天は第二軍を率いた
on Wangnan East Road
王南東路沿い
attack north
北を攻撃する
Beibeicun Company has a north-south attack
北北村中隊が南北攻撃
If you want to be in Tainan, you will lose
台南にいたいなら負けるよ
So anyone who visits Liao Naiyu knows that Nan Musi pad
したがって、リャオ・ナイユを訪れた人は誰でも、ナン・ムシ・パッドを知っています。
Moreover, Nan Musipad later went to the Sino-Japanese-Japanese-Australian War
さらに、ナン・ムシパドは後に日中日豪戦争に従軍した。
He also served as the governor of Taiwan, etc.
台湾総督なども務めた。
so very famous
とても有名です
but his status is absolutely high
しかし彼のステータスは間違いなく高い
But only as an escort
ただし教師としてのみ
because the possessed person said his name was Tanaka
取り憑かれた人が自分の名前をタナカと言っていたので
what and what
何と何
I don't know the name
名前が分かりません
Because I actually asked this princess
実際にこの姫に聞いてみたので
Because she is no longer called Tanaka Goto
もう田中後藤って呼ばれてないから
Sensing her main body again
再び本体を感知する
There are also a few ministers who say they are Tanaka Goto
田中後藤だと言っている大臣も何人かいる
the name just started
名前は始まったばかりです
i think he went by himself
彼は一人で行ったと思う
There is a Ph.D. from the Institute of Democracy, National Chengchi University
国立政治大学民主研究所で博士号取得者あり
Renmei
れんめい
When he is in 2020
彼が2020年にいるとき
Wrote a master's thesis
修士論文を書きました
may be the first
最初かもしれない
The first survey of Japanese gods in Taiwan
台湾初の日本の神様調査
It was written by a master student
修士課程の学生が書いたものです
When he went to work as an employee to do surveys
調査のために社員として出勤したとき
He just said he thought the three names
彼はその3人の名前を考えたとだけ言った
So the name of Japanese civilization is a bit unnatural
つまり、日本文明の名前は少し不自然です
It just doesn't look like a Japanese name.
とても日本人の名前とは思えません。
It is the Japanese name given by the Taiwanese themselves.
台湾人自身がつけた日本名です。
And tell the story from the start
そして最初からストーリーを話してください
When this temple was built, of course his story must be told
この寺院が建てられたとき、もちろん彼の物語は語られなければなりません
He said that all of them were with Tanakato
全員タナカトと一緒だと言ってた
The Wudanshe incident sent troops and they all died here
五丹社事件では軍隊が派遣され、全員がここで死亡した
Tanaka died then
田中さんはその後亡くなった
By 2006
2006年までに
Their host changed his name to Tanaka Steel Works
主人が田中製鋼所に名前を変えました
Tanaka Steel Works has its own people
田中製鋼所には人がいる
First Taipei County Magistrate
初代台北県判事
Tanaka Steel Works
田中製鋼所
When the Japanese took over Taiwan
日本軍が台湾を占領したとき
There are only three counties in Taiwan
台湾には3つの県しかない
Taipei County Taichung County Tainan County
台北県 台中県 台南県
The first Taipei county magistrate was Koko Tanaka
初代台北県判事は田中ココだった
Admiralty County
金鐘郡
Tanaka Steel Works was indeed in 1874
田中製鉄所は確かに1874年にあった
Sending troops to Taiwan is coming
台湾への派兵が近づいている
then interactive war
それからインタラクティブな戦争
not interactive war
インタラクティブな戦争ではない
Thought that the second year of Japan's war
日本の戦争2年目だと思ってた
Tanaka Steel Works led troops to attack Penghu
田中製鉄所が軍隊を率いて澎湖を攻撃
At that time, Taiwan had not given Japan
当時、台湾は日本に譲歩していませんでした。
Penghu was captured in March
澎湖島は3月に占領された
Tanaka Steel Works led the troops on four rear admirals
田中製鉄所は4人の少将が部隊を率いていた
led troops to besiege Penghu
軍隊を率いて澎湖を包囲した
So I became the first county magistrate of Taipei County
それで私は台北県の初代県令になりました
I think
私が思うに
because later
後でだから
don't know who
誰だか分からない
After textual research, it is said that
文献調査の結果、次のように言われています。
there is indeed a tanaka
確かにタナカがいる
But Tanaka Steel has this guy
でも田中鋼にはこんな奴がいる
Totsu Tanaka invented this by himself
田中徹さんが自ら考案したものです
so
それで
Not only Tanaka households were changed into Tanaka Steel Works
田中家だけが田中製鉄所になったわけではない
And originally there was a central Sichuan
そして元々は四川省の中央部にありました。
this weird japanese name
この奇妙な日本の名前
Naoki Honkawa
就改成本川直生
there is such a person
そんな人がいます
so
それで
don't know which one
どっちか分からない
Those who have studied Taiwan history
台湾の歴史を学んだことがある方
go may be pointing
goが指しているのかもしれない
So we have to adjust it to be more convincing and persuasive.
したがって、より説得力があり、説得力のあるものになるように調整する必要があります。
So the day of the real day came
こうして、本当の日がやって来た
Because at the beginning he said their Generalissimo Tanaka
なぜなら、最初に彼は彼らのジェネラリシモ・タナカと言ったからです。
Died here in 1874
1874年にここで亡くなった
But in fact, Gosho Tanaka later went to be a member of the Aristocratic Movement Council
しかし実際には、田中剛昌は後に貴族運動評議会の委員となった。
After leaving Taiwan, he went back to Japan to become a member of the noble movement
台湾を出国後、日本に戻り貴族運動の一員となる
This is the temple he took the Japanese god
ここは彼が日本の神様を祀った寺院です
But myths are created
しかし神話は作られる
but create convincing
しかし、説得力のあるものを作成する
unless you create a person who doesn't exist at all
まったく存在しない人物を作成しない限り
no one can question
誰も質問できない
Then you keep tying him to historical events.
そして彼を歴史的出来事に結び付け続けます。
You have to find a real historical figure
本当の歴史上の人物を見つけなければなりません
He has gone through such a process
彼はそのようなプロセスを経てきました
This is what Asean Palace looks like now
現在のアセアン宮殿はこんな感じです
The one in front of the ASEAN Palace was rebuilt in the past two years.
ASEAN宮殿の前にある宮殿はここ2年で再建された。
Behind him was a completely pure
彼の後ろには完全に純粋な人がいた
is a man's temple
男の神殿です
Then I guessed
それから私は推測しました
Did he suffer from that just now?
彼は今そのことで苦しんでいましたか？
The stimulation of Hongmaogang security group
紅毛港警備グループの刺激
The security regiment is beautifully covered
警備連隊は美しく覆われています
then business is good
それならビジネスはうまくいく
many people go
多くの人が行きます
So he put his name
そこで彼は自分の名前を出しました
Japanese style
趕成日本式的
a bit of Japanese society
日本社会を少しだけ
I know it's the Diet of Japan
それが日本の国会であることはわかっています
red chrysanthemum
赤い菊
look here
ここを見て
this is covered
これはカバーされています
in this temple
この寺院で
this is
これは
this is that
これはそれです
Okazo Tanaka
田中岡藏
Marshal Tanaka
タナカ元帥
Originally the earliest
元々は一番早い
is to do a
をすることです
Taiwan-style gods
台湾風の神様
General Tanaka
田中大元帥
later
後で
Sister Hua, why is she called a Japanese god?
華姉妹はなぜ日本の神様と呼ばれているのですか？
So just rebuild and make a
それで、リビルドして作成するだけです
Japanese look
和の風貌
This is very mussy point
ここは非常に厄介なポイントです
this is called
これは呼ばれます
Okay, I think these are the representatives of Japanese gods.
そうですね、これらは日本の神様の代表だと思います。
The reason why these Japanese gods were born
日本の神様が生まれた理由
In fact, it is consistent with the original national civil servants of the Taiwanese people who have a sense of urination.
実はこれは台湾人の排尿感覚のある本来の国家公務員と一致しているのです。
developed from there
そこから発展した
It's not that Taiwanese people particularly like Japanese gods or Japanese soldiers
台湾人が特に日本の神様や日本兵が好きなわけではない
No, just treat them as meritorious service
いや、功労者として扱ってください
It is a step forward with Taiwan and China.
台湾や中国との一歩前進だ。
Responsive faith actually starts with fear
反応的な信仰は実際には恐怖から始まります
or to cheer up
または元気づけるために
Why does the big temple control these small temples with merits?
なぜ大きな寺院が小さな寺院を功徳をもって経営するのでしょうか？
Because the gods with higher divinity are in Taiwan's view of gods
台湾の神観ではより神性の高い神が存在するため
able to manage or suppress
管理または抑制できる
Relatively low status, or this kind of ghosts become gods
比較的地位が低いとか、こういう幽霊が神になるとか
Non-orthodox god
非正統的な神
So I used to use urine called Yin pee Yinshen
だから私は陰小陰神という尿を使っていました
That is to say, it is not a righteous god
つまり正義の神ではない
It was built between ghosts and gods
幽霊と神の間に建てられた
that ghost can become a god
その幽霊は神になれる
ancestors died
先祖が死んだ
Actually become a ghost
本当に幽霊になる
generalized ghost
一般化された幽霊
But because you have descendants to worship
でもあなたには崇拝すべき子孫がいるから
So it doesn't really become a ghost
だから本当に幽霊にはならないんだよ
one day it will pass
いつかは過ぎてしまうだろう
may become a god going to heaven
天国に行く神になるかもしれない
This is the general traditional concept of ghosts and people in Taiwan
これが台湾の幽霊と人間に関する一般的な伝統的な概念です
that's how it came
それがこうして来た
This is how the concept of ghosts and gods came about
幽霊と神という概念はこうして生まれた
Because of the special environment in Taiwan
台湾の特殊な環境のため
so from fear you need
だから恐怖からあなたは必要とする
from fear to fear
恐怖から恐怖へ
From the soul
魂から
Overcome this later
後でそれを超えていきます
And then hope and pray
そして希望と祈りを捧げます
to pray for their blessing
彼らの祝福を祈るために
So will develop the whole
それで全体が発展します
faith in fairness
公平性への信頼
Chiayi has a place
嘉義には場所があります
There is a very special photocopy palace temple
非常に特別なコピー宮殿寺院があります
very small
非常小
please god god i can't remember
お願いです、神様、私は思い出せません
But when his god was born
しかし、彼の神が生まれたとき、
Usually we call
通常、私たちは電話します
acting hater
演技嫌い
When the god is born, there will be a canopy show
神々が生まれるとき、キャノピーショーが行われます
Whether it's a bad show or a song boy show
それがひどいショーであっても、ソングボーイのショーであっても
The most special place in that temple is
その寺院の最も特別な場所は
The day the god was born
神様が生まれた日
About
だいたい
Two or three hundred canopies are not a big deal
200 か 300 の天蓋は大したことではありません
Line up along the road
道路沿いに並ぶ
not along the road
道路沿いではない
Straight row
直線列
Those who are not very good play music over there
あまり上手じゃない人たちはあそこで音楽を演奏します
because no one is watching
誰も見てないから
No one actually went there to act
実際に行動するためにそこに行った人は誰もいません
It's just a bad car
ただのダメな車だよ
Then set up the set
次にセットをセットアップします
right there
すぐそこに
just someone
ただ誰か
this votive
この奉納物
donate money
お金を寄付する
every year
毎年
I haven't studied it
勉強していない
but i saw it once
でも一度見たことがある
startled
びっくりした
want to say what's going on
何が起こっているのか言いたい
This is also what I have
これも私が持っているものです
Taiwanese society has many unique features
台湾社会には多くの独特な特徴がある
Okay, the Japanese gods just mentioned
さて、先ほど述べた日本の神々について
In fact, most of it has to do with the war
実はそのほとんどが戦争に関係している
The concept of Taiwanese people's belief in Yungong is
台湾人の雲公信仰の概念は、
Actually don't care that you are the god of the country
あなたが国の神であることは実際には気にしないでください
As long as you die unexpectedly, it's important
予期せず死ぬ限り、それは重要です
or unknown
または不明
Then you showed up near my house
それからあなたは私の家の近くに現れました
I must help you worship Chaodu
チャオドゥを崇拝するのを手伝わなければなりません
let you upgrade, you come to dress up
アップグレードしてドレスアップしましょう
general social psychology
一般的な社会心理学
This social psychology existed 3,000 years ago
この社会心理学は3000年前に存在した
After 3000 there will still be
3000以降もまだあります
So this block of folk belief is definitely not going away
したがって、この民間信仰のブロックは決して消えることはありません
Science is flourishing and civilization is developing
科学は繁栄し、文明は発展しています
more books
もっと本を
When you meet the trapped shield one day
いつか閉じ込められた盾に出会ったら
Tell you it might be the one next to your house
それはあなたの家の隣かもしれないと教えてください
If you are lucky, you didn't go to worship
運が良ければ、礼拝に行かなかったかもしれません
then you will definitely go to worship
それなら必ず礼拝に行きます
Do you want to believe it or not
信じますか信じたくないですか
but i have nothing to lose
でも私には失うものは何もありません
so go ask
だから聞いてみましょう
It's really good to say goodbye
別れを言うのは本当に良いことだ
will have such a mentality
そういう精神を持つだろう
So Taiwan's Youyin apartment medicine
台湾の友陰団地医学
Later, there will be Japanese
後は日本人もいるよ
A tenth degree of eternal change in nature
自然的一個十級永變
produced
生産された
not really taiwanese
本当は台湾人ではない
I especially like the Japanese
特に日本人が好きです
nothing to do with this
これとは何の関係もありません
so
それで
Hengchun has one
恒春には1つあります
Yong Yin Po
ヨンインポー
This is also a legend
これも伝説です
But it's not true, I don't know
でもそれは真実じゃない、分からない
It is said that it will lead to misfortune
不幸を招くとも聞きます
Of course it's possible
もちろん可能です
times in the netherlands
オランダでの回
It is rumored that there was a disaster there
そこで災害があったという噂がある
There's a Dutch lady on it
オランダ人女性がいるよ
dead
死
so they put her on the spot
それで彼らは彼女をその場に置きました
bought
買った
then start doing
それからやり始める
The same is Indian apartment medicine
インドのアパート医学も同じです
what i just said
私が今言ったこと
That is to say, the Chinese people were corrupted by ghost officials
つまり、中国人は幽霊のせいで公務員を手に入れたのだ。
Taiwanese because of the sensory ghost civil servant
感覚幽霊公務員のため台湾人
And for a religion that has produced so many Japanese gods
そして、これほど多くの日本の神々を生み出してきた宗教にとっても、
The Psychology That Generates Pagan Religious Needs
異教の宗教的欲求を生み出す心理
Let me give you an example
例を挙げてみましょう
In 1949, Qianan Palace in Westport
1949年、ウェストポートの銭安宮殿
Xigang Thousand Shore Palace is very famous in Taiwan.
西港千海岸宮殿は台湾で非常に有名です。
National Folklore, Female Three-Year Teachers in Xigang
全国民俗学、西港の三年女教師
Did you hear about it in the official website just now?
先ほど公式サイトで知りましたか？
The Democratic Party is very special
民主党は特別だ
When the church was established in 1949
1949年に教会が設立されたとき
he has a rod
彼は棒を持っています
is a notice
お知らせです
Tell me why this year
なぜ今年なのか教えてください
Why do we need to build this teaching
なぜこの教えを構築する必要があるのか
The most interesting here are these
ここで最も興味深いのはこれらです
we are for
私たちはのためにいます
Chaoba Dadong has a war
チャオバ・ダドンは戦争をしている
Air Mountain Army
エアマウンテンアーミー
fallen soldiers
落ちた兵士
It is difficult to defend the country and the Ganyi Party
国と甘義党を守るのは難しい
and innocent people
そして無実の人々
we're all included
私たち全員が含まれています
Also beware of excess
過剰摂取にも注意
So regardless of status, regardless of country
だから地位に関係なく、国に関係なく
regardless of ethnicity
民族に関係なく
As long as there is war in Dadong
大東に戦争がある限り
The Great East Asian War is actually in Japanese
大東亜戦争は実は日本語で書かれている
Can't speak Chinese nouns
中国語の名詞が話せない
Anti-Japanese will not talk about the Great East Asian War
反日は大東亜戦争について語らない
Great East Asia War is a Japanese noun
大東亜戦争は日本語の名詞です
Because Taiwan came from there
台湾はそこから来たから
Or about the Great East Asian War?
それとも大東亜戦争のこと？
land, sea and air attack
陸、海、空からの攻撃
Crit is also in Japanese
クリティカルも日本語です
customary terms
慣習的な条件
soldiers of the armed forces
軍隊の兵士
all blah blah
何とか何とか
At this time, Lianli thinks about democratic operation
この時点で、Lianli は民主的運営について考えています
also by the way
ちなみに
This is a standard
これは標準です
this is written by a Taoist priest
これは道教の僧侶が書いたものです
access
訪問
Just tell me why we did it this time
なぜ今回それをしたのか教えてください
Such
そのような
The teaching of Jianjiao is
建教の教えは、
Large
大きい
Consciousness of sacrifice
祭祀的意識
I would say the point is
ポイントは次のとおりだと思います
such a mentality
そのような精神
fear fear like this
このような恐怖を恐れる
there are so many
とてもたくさんあります
because of the war
戦争のせいで
Due to various disasters
様々な災害により
people we need
私たちが必要とする人々
fuck them
クソ奴ら
Otherwise, it will be a very heavy society
そうしないととても重い社会になってしまう
The burden of the crowd will be related to ghosts
群衆の負担は幽霊に関係するだろう
This is the pie I just commissioned, in case you can’t see it clearly, so I zoomed in on it
これは私が依頼したばかりのパイです。はっきり見えないかもしれないので拡大してみました
Next, I want to quickly introduce our Japanese-style array
続いては和風配列を簡単にご紹介したいと思います
In addition to making a statement, there is now a trend
ステートメントを行うことに加えて、今ではトレンドがあります。
In some places, Japanese-style arrays are popular
場所によっては和風配列が人気
The head of the battle is the group performing at the temple fair
戦いの先頭は寺院の縁日でパフォーマンスするグループです
Wait a minute our time will be up so I'm going to speak very quickly
ちょっと待ってください、もう時間が終わりますので、急いで話します
I give two, one is called
私は2つを与えます、1つは呼ばれます
It's related to the magic driving show
マジック・ドライビング・ショーに関係しています
The other one is about cabaret
もう一つはキャバレーについてです
The previous one is related to the magic driving show
前のはマジックドライビングショー関連です
It's also a continuation of this tradition that is basically the Japanese era
基本的には日本の元号であるこの伝統の継続でもあります
Japanese Shrine Statement in Japan
日本神社在日本聲明
The gods of nearby Taiwan are usually invited to celebrate
通常、近隣の台湾の神々が祝賀行事に招待されます。
palace temple
宮殿寺院
God also came out
神様も出てきた
come out
出てくる
So now we can all find films from the 1930s, 40s
今では 1930 年代、40 年代の映画を見つけることができます。
You can see many gods and gods in Taiwanese temples will come out and have fun together
たくさんの神様に会えるし、台湾の寺院の神様も出てきて一緒に楽しみます
habit like this
このような習慣
This is a primary school student in Changhua Lugang in 1959
これは 1959 年、彰化鹿港の小学生です
Japanese shikigami
日本の式神
this is not very clear
これはあまり明確ではありません
Wear this costume in Japanese style
この衣装を和風に着てください
The most famous one is actually in Kaohsiung
最も有名なのは実は高雄にある
identify the area
エリアを特定する
Downstream of Round Creek on the second floor
ラウンドクリーク下流2階
first appeared
最初に登場した
yes
はい
Yu Yu
ゆうゆう
Mickey
ミッキー
is Japanese
日本人です
is god
神です
this god
この神
Shenyu is the religion
神佑は宗教です
discharge out parade
退院パレード
That
それか
It is expected that the Japanese-style front map we know now is probably the earliest.
おそらく現在知られている日本式前線図が最古のものではないかと予想されます。
I want details without telling
言わずに詳細が欲しい
the most important thing is to say
最も重要なことは言うことです
his form follows
彼のフォームは次のとおりです
The now more famous Bayley's is different
今では有名になったベイリーズは違います
But I think he's still older
でも彼はまだ年上だと思う
because of him
彼のせいで
The form of performance is relatively simple
演奏形式は比較的シンプル
then he has no music
それなら彼には音楽がない
his music is
彼の音楽は
to sing by myself
自分で歌うこと
what song
何の歌
this song
この曲
It is the song to be sung at the annual festivals of Taiwan shrines
台湾の神社の例祭で歌われる歌です。
This is clothing from the 1990s
1990年代の洋服です
depression team
うつ病チーム
This is the Depression team performance I went to film in 2008
これは私が2008年に撮影に行ったDepressionチームのパフォーマンスです
Let's show you a video
ビデオをお見せしましょう
girl
女の子
thank you
țiがとう
He rarely...
彼はめったに...
It's definitely time for you to attack the corner
コーナーを攻めるのは間違いない
should be...
そうあるべきです...
do you know he plays
彼が遊んでいることを知っていますか
he is here
彼はここにいます
he had that sport
彼はそのスポーツをしていた
yes, this...
はい、これ...
it's all in there
すべてはそこにある
they get A's
彼らはAを獲得します
this file number
このファイル番号
Will there be a formal one?
正式なものはあるのでしょうか？
he felt the time was short
彼は時間が短いと感じた
He has vision time
彼にはビジョンタイムがある
There are 24, 25
24、25あります
Then there are 24, 25
それから24、25です
kid
子供
this is not your horn
これはあなたのクラクションではありません
Old Fast Hey
オールドファストヘイ
Old Gao
オールド・ガオ
lens
レンズ
On the Press small screen
プレス小画面で
He said 15
彼は15と言った
So what does he mean by being funny now?
では、彼が今面白いと言うのはどういう意味でしょうか？
Everyone must hear this song
誰もがこの曲を聞く必要があります
Wait a minute and change the song they sing
ちょっと待って、歌う曲を変えてください
you feel like hearing again
また聞きたいような気がします
The song they sang is the song of the Taiwan shrine
彼らが歌った歌は台湾神社の歌です
this song
この曲
Everyone must hear this song
誰もがこの曲を聞く必要があります
Wait a minute and change the song they sing
ちょっと待って、歌う曲を変えてください
you feel like hearing again
また聞きたいような気がします
The song they sang is the song of the Taiwan shrine
彼らが歌った歌は台湾神社の歌です
everyone heard
誰もが聞いた
Song
歌
This is their elementary school
ここは彼らの小学校です
middle school singer
中学生の歌手
please listen
聞いて下さい
mostly foreign
ほとんど外国人
Let's watch this elementary school song
この小学校の歌を見てみましょう
This shrine is going to be in this place
この神社はこの場所に建つ予定です
but represents the pair of mysterious nouns
しかし、謎の名詞のペアを表します
This is the closest
これが一番近いです
he was thinking
彼は考えていた
very showy
とても派手な
It's Japanese gods
日本の神様です
It is the mysterious term of the Japanese Church
それは日本の教会の謎の用語です
Their performance is actually very simple
彼らのパフォーマンスは実際には非常にシンプルです
But it's fun
でも楽しいよ
They just sang this song.
彼らはちょうどこの歌を歌ったところです。
This is the Taiwan National Anthem.
これは台湾国歌です。
The Taiwan National Anthem's annual ceremony is on October 28th.
台湾国歌斉唱式は10月28日に行われる。
The whole Taiwan is going to be on holiday.
台湾全土が休暇に入ります。
The kids are going to be on holiday.
子供たちは休暇を取る予定です。
This is the time to celebrate and sing this song.
今こそこの歌を祝い、歌う時です。
When I first heard them sing, I didn't understand what they were singing.
初めて彼らの歌を聞いたとき、何を歌っているのか分かりませんでした。
I asked a 70-year-old teacher.
70歳の先生に聞きました。
I said what are you laughing at?
何を笑ってるの？と私は言いました。
you say
あなたは言う
I have no idea
何も思いつきません
we used to
私たちはかつて
It is passed down from generation to generation by the previous family
先代から代々受け継がれてきた
but i know he just said
でも私は彼が今言ったことは知っています
He knows the first sentence is called
彼は最初の文が次のように呼ばれることを知っています
Wait a minute, Mazu has old people
ちょっと待ってください、媽祖には老人がいます
I said
私は言いました
I'll record it once you sing it
歌ったら録音します
Wait a moment
等一下
this is what we see
これが私たちが見ているものです
Taiwan Times reporter song was sung like this by him
台湾タイムズの記者の歌を彼はこう歌った
he doesn't know what he's singing
彼は自分が何を歌っているのか分かりません
But take that tape
でもそのテープを取ってください
From generation to generation
世代から世代へ
from the 1950s
1950年代から
We are now from the 1920s
私たちは今、1920年代から来ています
He is still singing, and every kid has to sing
彼は今も歌っている、そしてすべての子供たちは歌わなければならない
Later, I finally found the genuine version, let me show you
その後、ようやく正規版を見つけたので紹介します
My name is my lord, the lord of the Jun family
私の名前は私の主、ジュン家の主です
Someone should know the two gentlemen. He is my recent colleague.
誰かがこの二人の紳士を知っているはずです。彼は私の最近の同僚です。
Recently, the researcher Mr. Huang Fujing retired
最近、研究者の黄楓静氏が退職しました。
Because I think there must be something wrong with this song, I need to ask him
この曲には何か問題があると思うので、彼に尋ねなければなりません
As soon as he heard it, he said this when I was in elementary school
それを聞いてすぐに小学生の時にこう言った。
I have to sing it once a year, I'll come and I'll sing it for you
年に一度は歌わないといけない、私が来てあなたのために歌ってあげる
Central will sing the first season of Taipei
セントラルは台北の最初のシーズンを歌います
Because it has reached the end of the war and can no longer be tolerated in Taiwan
戦争が終わり、台湾ではもう許されないから
So I changed it to Cup Old Street made by Grandma Curry
ということでカレーおばあちゃんの作ったカップオールドストリートに変更しました
very interesting
とても興味深い
Like I just said, empty door flower breakfast at night is empty door flower
さっき言ったように、空のドアの花、夜の朝食は空のドアの花です
Okay, let's introduce another similar
さて、似たようなものをもう一つ紹介しましょう
appeared a few years later than him
彼より数年遅れて登場した
Then I think the south and north sides of the second floor of the gate are in the bay of Tainan City.
そうすると門の2階の南側と北側は台南市の湾に入っていると思います。
Wanniandian in this area builds a school every 12 years
この地域の万年店は 12 年ごとに学校を建設します
It is determined that teaching will be established once every 10 years or so
10年に一度くらいの割合で教育が確立されると決まっている
The biggest feature of this area is that it has a lot of soil-like shock heads
このエリアの最大の特徴は、土のようなショックヘッドがたくさんあることです。
Until recently, people in the village organized it themselves
これまで村の人々は組織化してきました。
then come out and circle into the show
それから出てきてショーの中に入ります
This is hard to find in Taiwan now.
現在台​​湾では入手困難となっております。
So they were in the same class as their elementary and middle school classmates that day
つまり、その日彼らは小中学校の同級生と同じクラスだったのだ。
Students and classmates went to participate in the front performance
学生やクラスメイトが前演に参加しに行きました
The Outer Years Electricity Corps started in 1954
アウターイヤーズ電力隊は 1954 年に発足
It was expanded in 1962
1962年に拡張されました
and it continues until now
そしてそれは今まで続いています
never stopped
決して止まらなかった
only comes out every 12 years
12年に一度しか出ない
This is the most gorgeous front in Taiwan
ここは台湾で最も華やかな前線です
You can take a look
見てみることができます
he is already
彼はすでに
Because I wrote this
これを書いたから
The person who made up this array is
この配列を作った人は
At that time, there were four people who had read
その時読んだ人は4人でした。
in the bay
湾の中で
eel's
うなぎの
fish rice
魚飯
But they are doing wholesale
しかし、彼らは卸売を行っています
have read
読んだ
Then let me give you a little explanation
それでは少し説明させていただきます
His soundtrack is more particular
彼のサウンドトラックはより特別です
There is also this Yuyu performance
こんなゆゆパフォーマンスもあります
Then later added the Japanese Wu
その後、日本の呉が追加されました
I think he improved on the top version
彼はトップバージョンよりも改善されたと思います
more professional and better looking
よりプロフェッショナルで見た目も良くなりました
he has three dances
彼は3つのダンスを持っています
wait a minute we'll show you one
ちょっと待ってください、一つお見せします
In fact, we see that there is only one paragraph in the relationship.
実際、関係には段落が 1 つしかないことがわかります。
let me explain to you first
まず説明させてください
This is the Yutuan in Wanli. When they go out, there are seventy or eighty people in this group, and there are close to 100 people.
ここは万里の玉団で、出かけるときは70～80人、100人近くになります。
This is a temple city. You can see that there is a stage here. The stage is facing the gate of the temple.
ここは門前都市で、門に面して舞台があるのがわかります。
Standard he these nice big penetrations are fine
標準的な彼はこれらの素晴らしい大きな貫通は問題ありません
he performed
彼は演奏した
This is the outskirts of the village after he came in
ここは彼が来た後の村の外れです
This is the gate of Damiaocheng Temple
こちらは大满城寺の門です
they are here
彼らはここにいます
He must go around first
彼はまず立ち回らなければならない
and then come in from the middle
そして真ん中から入ってくる
The official performance is tentatively scheduled to begin
正式公演開始予定
This is his standard specification
これが彼の標準仕様です
If it's a real formal performance
本当の正式な演奏なら
Three paragraphs and five paragraphs must be performed
3段落と5段落を実行する必要があります
wait a minute is a show
ショーを見るには少しお待ちください
Because he went around and passed through this temple
ぐるっと回ってこのお寺を通ったので
and in a hurry
そして急いで
so just a song and dance
だから歌とダンスだけ
good
良い
Then we got a little familiar with the song
それから私たちはその曲に少し慣れました
Because we are going to primary school
うちは小学校に行くから
I sang this song in music class
音楽の授業でこの歌を歌いました
Shu Wu Muran
シュー・ウー・ムーラン
he wants to go around first
彼は最初に歩き回りたいと思っています
Excuse me
すみません
A few old gentlemen will be able to serve
数人の老紳士が奉仕できるだろう
Founding
創業
When I went that time
その時行った時は
The four founding members
創業メンバー4人
still business
まだ営業中
commercial almost eighty years old
商業的にはほぼ80歳
walk in this scene
このシーンの中を歩く
In fact, they are very proud
実際、彼らはとても誇りに思っています
They created a political arena
彼らは政治の舞台を作り上げた
Since 1994
1994年以降
this is the first
これが最初です
Xie Lang
謝朗
Koro
小郎
There will be side covers inside
内側にはサイドカバーが入ります
Jin Xiang Yuan
ジン・シャンユアン
his flag doesn't matter
彼の旗は関係ない
because the flag is in the middle
旗が真ん中にあるから
The sides are their alignment
側面はそれらの位置合わせです
People in this place are very patriotic
この場所の人々はとても愛国心が強い
when traveling here
ここを旅行するとき
First
初め
walk ahead of the line
列の前を歩く
Another flag
別のフラグ
But they are at most this homestay
でも、彼らはせいぜいこのホームステイくらいです
In fact, it is for
実際、それはのためです
recoil
反動
it's folk wisdom
それは民間の知恵です
because this is
なぜならこれは
they are familiar
彼らはよく知っています
I like it very much
私はそれがとても好き
think it looks good
良さそうだと思う
politics
政治
But in the 1950s and six years
しかし 1950 年代と 6 年間
anti-democratic atmosphere
反民主的な雰囲気
very romantic
とてもロマンチック
under this circumstance
この状況下では
This is a very change of seasons
まさに季節の変わり目ですね
So they figured out a way
そこで彼らはある方法を考え出した
first interval
最初の間隔
Because the previous director was an interval
前監督がインターバルだったので
This is really from the unit until now
これは本当にユニットから今までです
with no change
変化なし
Why did you choose Shu Ao Luren?
なぜシュウ・アオ・ルーレンを選んだのですか？
I started
始めた
I'm thinking now, too, for the first time
私も今初めて思います
Why is it because of patriotism
なぜ愛国心のためなのか
Not only every other period, but also sing Chinese private
隔期だけでなく、中国語のプライベートも歌います
Or ask someone from your choir
または、合唱団の誰かに聞いてください
They are actually very particular about sound
実は音にもすごくこだわっているんです
They chose this song because of his rhythm
彼らは彼のリズムのためにこの曲を選びました
suitable time to enter
入場に適した時間帯
very slow
非常に遅い
he is rhythmic
彼はリズミカルです
Sound and rhythm are considered
音とリズムを考慮
no choice
選択の余地ない
Then he didn't know that this was called Shu Aolu
それから彼はこれがShu Aoluと呼ばれていることを知りませんでした
because of this song
この曲のせいで
In 1933 there was a record company in Taiwan
1933年、台湾にレコード会社がありました。
called
呼ばれた
Colombia
コロンビア
Gullenmea
グレンメア
released an album
アルバムをリリースしました
It's a vocalist from Tainan named Lin Shihang
林詩航という台南出身のボーカリストです。
Sing
歌う
this song turned into a song
この歌は歌になりました
A love song called civilized love
文明化された愛というラブソング
is a love song
ラブソングです
So they choose civilized love
だから彼らは文明的な愛を選ぶ
let's make this background music
このBGMを作ってみましょう
I didn't know this was Su Wu Festival
蘇呉祭だったとは知りませんでした
ok, after coming in
はい、入ってから
they have three shows
彼らは3つのショーを持っています
this is part of it
これはその一部です
called fish three dance
フィッシュスリーダンスと呼ばれる
I'm afraid to call this Yu Sanwu
これをユ・サンウと呼ぶのは怖い
But this show is already a classic
しかし、このショーはすでに古典的です
the first thing i saw was a fish
最初に見たのは魚でした
they are professional fish
彼らはプロの魚です
I didn't expect that they were all local gentlemen.
彼らが全員地元の紳士だったとは思いませんでした。
Mainly there are masters in middle schools, public schools, and cities
主に中学校、公立学校、都市部にマスターがいます
Twenty dancing ladies are golden cats playing blood
20人の踊る女性は血を奏でる金色の猫です
after dancing
踊った後
golden wheel four
金輪月四
skip to twenty
20までスキップ
Bend this area
この部分を曲げます
A total of nine female
女性は計9名
a big conflict
大きな衝突
now later population show
今すぐ人口ショー
now i have six
今私は6つ持っています
good
良い
A prop is very particular
小道具は非常に特殊です
This is Li Long's premium product
これはLi Longのプレミアム製品です
one thousand dollars to buy
買うのに1000ドル
no one bought it for you
誰もあなたのために買ってくれなかった
I'm wearing this
これを着ています
Taiwan is called Tabit
台湾はタビットと呼ばれます
The Japanese of the Japanese era is called the main generation
日本統治時代の日本人を主流世代と呼ぶ
He is lost
彼は迷っています
This is specially made
これは特別に作られたものです
because the shoes are not available now
その靴は今は手に入らないので
I was supposed to wear the splints.
副木を着用することになっていました。
The kind worn in Japanese ensembles
和装で着用されるタイプ
But they want to bypass the ticket
しかし彼らはチケットを回避したいのです
I've been wearing it for too long and I'm uncomfortable
長時間履いていて不快になった
so hurry up
だから急いで
rush through this
これを駆け抜けて
This is a shoe from the Japanese era
これは日本時代の靴です
Also pinched
もつままれた
it dance too
それも踊る
What we usually see with the eyes
私たちが普段目で見ているもの
is very brief
とても短いです
is a girl
少女です
Look at that little girl just now
今あの小さな女の子を見てください
decide on the brand
ブランドを決める
It's all fake
それはすべて偽物です
when they look in the mirror
彼らが鏡を見るとき
wear that too
それも着て
will be full of hard work
大変な仕事でいっぱいになるだろう
And hand fog
そしてハンドフォグ
It turned out to be only this
これだけだったことが判明
It's you who pity this
これを哀れむのはあなたです
Theologian
神学者
This is the family background
これが家族背景です
Many people should know this song
この曲を知っている人も多いはず
almost nothing
ほとんど何もない
what is singing
何を歌っているのか
you can't hear clearly
はっきりと聞こえません
There are... all samples
サンプルはすべてあります
please sing
歌ってください
This is singing you can't hear clearly
これははっきりと聞こえない歌です
Hong Kong Ice 13 Fanxian
香港アイス 13 ファンシアン
come aton
オールaton
imme
今
bottom cooper
下クーパー
Vin
来て
woke up
破る
yes
はい
sucked
パン
really
真
lyrics
歌詞
Halloween
ハロウィン
Vocaloid
ボーカロイド
thank you
ありがとう
Japanese women should sound like this
日本人女性はこう言うべきだ
They are called Bai Dali
彼らはバイ・ダリと呼ばれています
have arrived at a non-ordinary
非日常に到達した
The deceased passed through the heart individual such
故人はそのような個人の心を通過しました
Don't worship Dali
ダリを崇拝するな
This is the religion
これが宗教です
Foreigners must teach at least one lap
外国人は少なくとも1周は指導しなければならない
This is Bai Dali
バイ・ダリです
It's all their own invention
それはすべて彼ら自身の発明です
Japanese
日本人
If you only go to Japan
日本だけに行くなら
that god
あの神
their religion
彼らの宗教
definitely not this
絶対にこれではありません
hard
難しい
Only he has this voice
この声を持っているのは彼だけだ
That pace is their own invention
そのペースは彼ら自身の発明です
Then there is no Shintoism in Japan
じゃあ日本には神道はないのか
There are two big benevolent hearts ahead
その先には二つの大きな慈悲の心がある
That is our so-so Mazu, that so-and-so
それは私たちのまあまあの媽祖です、あれはまあまあです
world to use
使える世界
So this is the rationale for Taiwan and Japan
これが台湾と日本の論理的根拠です
Come on guys we see flags all around
さあ、あちこちに旗が見えます
oh where do i press
ああ、どこを押せばいいですか
good
良い
As far as my early economic
私の初期の経済状況に関して言えば、
while marching here
ここを行進している間
Talk here and eat
ここで話して、食べて
pre-economic
経済以前の
ok let's hurry back and get this
よし、急いで戻ってこれを取りに行こう
because of today's time
今日の時間のせいで
I would like to introduce a Shulan Town later.
蜀蘭鎮については後ほど紹介したいと思います。
It also originated from this place
こちらも由来となっています
there is no time
時間がありません
This is also a solid proof of the adaptation of Japanese songs
これも日本の歌の翻案の確かな証拠です
ok, but this should show you guys
わかりましたが、これで皆さんにわかるはずです
This is a simple performance in the process of going around
一周する過程での簡単なパフォーマンスです
well , this is their religion
まあ、これが彼らの宗教です
What about the religion?
宗教についてはどうですか？
Let it go...what the hell is it?
放っておいてください...一体何ですか？
They have set up new Zhongshan since 1954
彼らは1954年以来新しい中山を設立しました
This time in 2008, I went to shoot in New Zhongshan
今回は2008年に新中山に撮影に行きました
In the old days of Japan, the god Amaterasu was placed in the Shinto religion of Japan
日本の昔、天照大神は日本の神道に位置づけられていました。
or the emperor
または皇帝
He said that it has been changed now, and of course Japanese gods can no longer be displayed
現在は変更されており、当然日本の神様は表示できなくなったとのこと
Well, what god can represent China?
さて、中国を代表する神は何でしょうか？
For the sake of political correctness, it is very clear to place the new Zhongshan
ポリティカル・コレクトネスの観点から、新しい中山を配置することは非常に明白です。
I just saw that there is one in the top god religion
上位神教にあるのを今見ました
that
それか
Fascinated by evil Buddha
邪悪な仏陀に魅せられて
They released Sun Yat-sen
彼らは孫文を釈放した
Sun Yat-sen has been released until now
孫文はこれまでに公開されています
Because the one who founded the group said
なぜなら、グループを立ち上げた人がこう言ったからです。
Let's think about who is the greatest in China
中国で誰が一番偉いか考えてみましょう
The Republic of China at that time
当時の中華民国
Just changed to the Republic of China
中華民国に変わったばかり
After much deliberation, only the father of the country, Sun Yat-sen,
熟慮の末、国の父である孫文だけが、
So put the portrait of Sun Yat-sen in
孫文の肖像画を入れてください
This is
これは
from another place
別の場所から
This Yu Yutuan later came from Wanli
このYu Yutuanは後に万里から来たものです
Go this way and spread out around here
こっちに行ってこの辺に広がって
Several villages have this organization
いくつかの村にはこの組織があります
It's all taught by the original
すべては原作から教わったことだ
then Hualien
それから花蓮
there is one
ここに一つ
Hakka Village
客家村
they learn
彼らは学びます
So they have a group called Yi Nation
彼らには Yi Nation というグループがあります
Otherwise it is very simple
それ以外の場合は非常に簡単です
they didn't dance
彼らは踊らなかった
That's where I'll be where their inspiration comes from
そこが私が彼らのインスピレーションの源となる場所です
Okay, I was going to introduce this Shuran bid certificate
さて、このシュラン入札証明書を紹介するつもりでした
Because this is only starting in 1966
だってこれは1966年に始まったばかりだから
Now it is very common outside southern Taiwan
現在では台湾南部以外でも非常に一般的です
But they are all professional certificates and insurance
しかし、それらはすべて専門的な証明書と保険です
The original evidence is very special.
元の証拠は非常に特別です。
This is a village Taiwanese costume
ここは台湾服の村です
Because it was the last lesson, they changed it again
最後のレッスンだったのでまた変更してもらいました
I used to wear Japanese clothes
昔は和服を着ていました
This is the standard of wearing Japanese clothes
これが和服の着こなしのスタンダードです
The main program of this is
このメインプログラムは、
He looks like a Japanese certificate head
日本の免許証の局長みたいだね
In fact, his content is talking about the customs of marriage in Taiwan
実は彼の内容は台湾の結婚習慣について語っているのです。
So there are six and a half years, and there is still a platform for a paddle ride
6年半経ちましたが、まだパドルライド用のプラットフォームがあります
The most important thing is to have a urinal
一番大事なのは小便器があること
In the past, there must be Miaotong in the driving suits that Taiwan paid for.
かつては台湾が費用を出したドライビングスーツを着たミャオトンもいたに違いない。
You have to be of a certain age to know
ある程度の年齢に達していないと分からない
Because there were no flush toilets before
昔は水洗トイレがなかったので
The bride just got married and you shouldn't wash out in the middle of the night to go to the bathroom
花嫁は結婚したばかりだから、夜中に体を洗ってトイレに行ってはいけません
so there must be a urinal
だから小便器があるはずだ
Urine or chamber pot in the room
室内の尿またはチャンバーポット
So one of the standard equipment of the dowry is the urine bucket
結納金の標準装備の一つが尿バケツです
So there's that show in their show
彼らのショーにはそのショーがあります
Then those dowries are all Taiwanese style
そしてその持参金はすべて台湾式です
But wearing Japanese clothes and dancing Japanese dances
でも和服を着て日本舞踊を踊る
I told him a story about a marriage custom in Taiwan
私は彼に台湾の結婚習慣の話をしました
So it's another big mix
これはまた大きなミックスです
This is the dowry, the previous dowry used this
これは持参金です、前の持参金はこれを使用しました
That means matchmaker
それは仲人を意味します
This is the matchmaker again
これまた仲人さんです
This is a sixth grade student
こちらは6年生です
Then his standard equipment will be followed by two people with five or four knives
その後、彼の標準装備に、5 つまたは 4 つのナイフを持った 2 人が続きます。
protect the team
チームを守る
Those two with five or four knives, you have to perform
5本か4本のナイフを持った二人、あなたはパフォーマンスをしなければなりません
Due to time constraints, I can't show you the video today
時間の都合上、今日は動画をお見せできません
The most important thing is that this kind of custom is good for the Japanese people and the Japanese-style formation
最も重要なことは、このような習慣が日本人にとって良いものであり、日本式フォーメーションであるということです。
It has nothing to do with cultural identity, or democratic identity, or national identity
それは文化的アイデンティティ、民主主義的アイデンティティ、国家的アイデンティティとは何の関係もありません
Basically, it is an element on the ground, which naturally diffuses and expands as the core
基本的には地上の要素であり、それを核として自然に拡散・膨張します。
Therefore, traditional Chinese, Taiwanese and Chinese traditional ghost priests are suitable for carrying one of the most important elements of these Japanese gods
したがって、伝統的な中国、台湾、中国の伝統的な幽霊僧侶は、これら日本の神の最も重要な要素の1つを担うのに適しています。
Not because of the uniqueness of these Japanese gods
日本の神々がユニークだからではない
This Japanese-style array is actually a living memory
この和風の配列は、実は生きた記憶なのです
For them, this is very lively, very good-looking, and they just want
彼らにとって、これはとても活気があり、とても見栄えがよく、ただ欲しいだけなのです。
Want to but feel that there is a political taboo, so they come up with ways to fight
政治的タブーがあると感じたくても、彼らは戦う方法を考え出す
Go in with the story of Taiwan, and it is more beautiful with Japanese clothes
台湾の物語に浸り、和服を着るとより美しくなります
I think it is more beautiful to package Japanese dance to perform
日本舞踊をパッケージ化して踊った方が美しいと思う
There's a video of this
これのビデオがあります
because of time
時間のせいで
I'm sorry because everyone talked too much today
今日はみんなしゃべりすぎてごめんなさい
so speak too slowly too early
だから話すのが遅すぎたり早すぎたりする
So there is no way to show you more videos
したがって、これ以上のビデオを表示する方法はありません
I think I'll stop here thank you all
ここでやめておこうと思います、皆さんありがとうございました
that i think time flies
時間が経つのは早いと思います
It's almost two hours and we don't feel tired at all.
約2時間ですが、まったく疲れを感じません。
Because Director Xie Wei Wei came
シェ・ウェイウェイ監督が来てくれたので
very lively and interesting
とても活気があって面白い
I'll take about the same amount of time, shall we allow three questions?
同じくらいの時間をいただきますが、質問を 3 つさせていただきますか。
It's good if you have time
時間があれば良いです
Thank you teacher for your wonderful speech
先生、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました
I want to turn around and ask
振り返って問いたい
That is to say, the teacher told us at the beginning
つまり、先生が最初に私たちに言いました。
Faith tomorrow he has no scriptures
明日の信仰には経典がない
He also has no institutionalized ritual
彼には制度化された儀式もありません
However, the scriptures of early Buddhism were all passed down orally.
しかし、初期仏教の経典はすべて口頭で伝えられました。
The teacher's speech today also runs through the concept of ghosts and gods
今日の先生のスピーチにも幽霊と神という概念が貫かれています。
Can't this be a word of mouth?
これは口頭ではないでしょうか？
if so
もしそうなら
So our folk beliefs can also be regarded as a kind of
したがって、私たちの民間信仰も一種の信仰とみなすことができます。
something systematic
体系的なもの
He can't do anything about these rumors
彼はこれらの噂について何もできません
write it as a systematic document
体系的な文書として書く
can't be called classic
クラシックとは言えない
basically the same
基本的に同じです
is there any other
他にありますか
I just want to ask
ただ聞きたいのですが
guide if you can
できればガイドしてください
I want to say can you
言いたいのですが、できますか
Because in Japanese memory
なぜなら日本人の記憶では
In fact, there are many elements in our post-ten years period
実際、ポスト10年には多くの要素があります。
Today's focus is on religion
今日の焦点は宗教です
but i'm facing the person
でも私はその人と向き合っている
For example, the corporate culture of the Tainan Gang
例えば、台南ギャングの企業文化。
Or the part of the business operation
または事業運営の一環
Or in our language Taiwanese
または私たちの言語である台湾語で
In fact, there are many Japanese elements in it
実は日本的な要素もたくさん入っているんです
I don't know about this part
この部分についてはわかりません
Let Yunyue help us introduce
Yuyue に紹介を手伝ってもらいましょう
Thanks
ありがとう
Parliament bar
国会バー
i think i'm in your consciousness
私はあなたの意識の中にあると思います
this range is too big
この範囲は大きすぎます
some not necessarily in japan
必ずしも日本にあるとは限りません
Actually we thought
実は私たちはこう思っていました
There are many Japanese in Taiwanese
台湾人には日本人が多い
foreign language
外国語
Many Japanese are borrowed from the West
日本人の多くは西洋から借りてきたものだ
Fake fat here
ここに偽の脂肪があります
we don't say fake bread
私たちは偽のパンとは言いません
eat bread you fake fat
パンを食べて太ったふりをする
It turns out that fat is Japanese
デブは日本人であることが判明
Actually fat is not Japanese
実はデブは日本人ではない
Fat is Spanish or French
デブはスペイン人かフランス人
called fat
脂肪と呼ばれる
so it is
それはそうです
There are several layers
いくつかの層があります
In fact, Taiwan has many
実は台湾にはたくさんの
Gay Taiwan from Holland
オランダ出身のゲイ台湾人
There are traces left to this day
今でもその痕跡が残っている
only chance
唯一のチャンス
We can all come and explore slowly
みんなでゆっくり探検しに来てください
Features of Taiwanese Culture
台湾文化の特徴
It's good to go through such a different regime
こんなに違う体制を経験するのは良いことだ
signals of different cultures
異文化の信号
none of them are completely gone
どれも完全に消えていない
and we'll get through
そして私たちは乗り越えます
And will produce the last Taiwan
そして最後の台湾を生み出すだろう
Stomach stuff
胃的東西
only a few simple
ほんの少しだけ簡単な
South of Taiwan to South of Taiwan
台湾南部から台湾南部へ
You can find a lot of iron scissors now
今ではアイロンハサミもたくさん見つかりますよ
Iron scissors will appear on the wall
壁に鉄のハサミが出現します
that is a construction of a building
それは建物の建設です
If you go to Europe, Northern Europe, Central Europe, Northern Europe to see
ヨーロッパ、北欧、中欧、北欧に行くなら
Houses from the 15th and 16th centuries have this on them
15世紀から16世紀の家にはこれが描かれています
Because it's just wood and iron pieces go in
木と鉄片が入っているだけなので
extended outside fixed
外側に伸ばして固定する
It has various tricks that you will see abroad
海外で見られるさまざまな仕掛けが施されている
But no one has ever made scissors
でも誰もハサミを作ったことがない
Make it into scissors in Taiwan
台湾でハサミにする
attached to the wall
壁に取り付けられた
Why because scissors are part of Taiwan's national religion
ハサミは台湾の国教の一部だからだ
Fart oblique is a very important magic weapon
斜めのおならは非常に重要な魔法の武器です
so it's called a feast
だからそれはお祭りと呼ばれます
It's what the Chinese People's Political Consultative Conference suppressed.
それは中国人民政治協商会議が弾圧したものだ。
Combining with the needs of western architectural construction
西洋建築のニーズとの融合
Plus the needs of Taiwanese folk beliefs
加えて台湾の民間信仰のニーズ
These two are very well combined
この2つはとてもよく組み合わされています
in Tainan
台南で
The nearest one, you can go out to the train station and there is a Xihuatang in front of you
一番近いのは駅を出て目の前に西華堂があります
a catastrophe church
大惨事の教会
there is that temple
あのお寺があります
can see these things
これらのものを見ることができます
This is the technology left by the Dutch
これはオランダ人が残した技術です
this one in Taiwan
これは台湾にある
The influence of this foreign culture is actually very diverse.
この異文化の影響は実に多様です。
That's why Taiwan's multiculturalism is formed
だからこそ台湾の多文化主義が形成される
This is one of the characteristics of Taiwanese culture
これは台湾文化の特徴の一つです
We also allow the last question
最後の質問も許可します
That Taiwanese God Song
あの台湾の神曲
that song by that mazdi
あのマズディのあの曲
the one that can be written
書けるもの
permission can be provided to us
許可を当社に与えることができます
good
良い
good internet
良いインターネット
I just had that on it
ちょうどそれが載ってた
if you need you keep that
必要ならそれを保管しておいてください
information to me
私への情報
proof of contact
連絡先の証明
It’s no problem to pass on the information to me and you.
私とあなたに情報を伝えるのは問題ありません。
I provide a photo to tell you
お伝えするために写真を提供します
that that
それは
Deep natural feel wind smooth wind mildew giant jaw
深い自然な感触の風 滑らかな風 カビの巨大な顎
The teacher said that two-day students
先生は、2日間の学生はこう言いました。
Now there is a third one, you can go and have a look
今では 3 番目のものができました。行って見てください。
good
良い
you actually use
あなたが実際に使っている
there might be that pop
あのポップもあるかもしれない
But the last one was mainly for sightseeing
でも最後のは主に観光用でした
I know
知っている
I think the one in Gaosi Village actually has the purpose of sightseeing
高四村のものは観光が目的だと思います
because it's late again
また遅いから
we thank you again thank you sir
改めて感謝いたします、ありがとうございます
brilliant speech
素晴らしいスピーチ
Thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
Thank you for participating
ご参加いただきありがとうございます